<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title/><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.140.1</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 12:41:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://liuqiran.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Digitization</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-11-27-digitization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 12:41:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-11-27-digitization/</guid><description>&lt;p>I will try to digitize all of my diaries. It’s a very big project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing freely</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-10-25-writing-freely/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:17:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-10-25-writing-freely/</guid><description>&lt;p>Now I find my writing skill is gradually improving. My writing speed is faster than before. The problem is that I face some stress when I need to post publicly. I’m still afraid of showing the errors and flaws of my article.&lt;br>
But I know no one can be perfect. Modifying the article and checking the grammar incessantly will kill the interest and motivation of writing.&lt;br>
In addition, It’s my own website. I think if other people don’t like, they can unfollow me.&lt;br>
In any case, I will try our best to practice more and share my thoughts which I think valuable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Harm from technology</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-29-harm-from-technology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 16:03:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-29-harm-from-technology/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my opinion, the real harmful radiation is from the devices in our daily life. When we are using our smartphone or other electronic tools, it’s possible to be exposed to radiation. Some people think the radition from phone is not enough to cause negative effect to our body. I take a sceptical attitude.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 14 Information quality</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-22-ep-14-information-quality/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:52:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-22-ep-14-information-quality/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my own opinion, there are three kinds of information in our life.&lt;br>
The first one is text, the second is audio, the last one is video.&lt;br>
Let’s talk about the first one. The content of texts is based on words. It’s the most abstract form of information. If we are literate, we can understand words, then we can understand road signs, posters, magazines, and books. It’s simplest to save texts for us. It’s also a form that can save the best information quality. But it’s maybe the hardest information to understand. Books contain the deepest information quality.&lt;br>
Audio is another kind of information, it’s based on sounds. It’s more natural to us because we can use our ear to understand. But we can’t control the speed of understanding. We probably also receive some useless information.&lt;br>
The third one is video. It combines sound and image. We can understand it very well, but it’s more shallow. Normally, information quality of video is not that good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Healthy food</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-15-healthy-food/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 15:45:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-15-healthy-food/</guid><description>&lt;p>Healthy food: Salmon, saurekrout, pecan, olive oil, (cod) liver, arugula, hamburger meat. These foods have the highest nutrients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 13 Anki and offline</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-08-ep-13-anki-and-offline/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 13:44:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-08-ep-13-anki-and-offline/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had been using Anki as my reviewing tool from 2017.&lt;br>
Anki is a very powerful and effective tool, it’s also one of the best tools for learning a language. There is also no alternative of Anki as a tool for creating your own database.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I gradually felt its disadvantages. It’s a software. I always need to use it on computer or on smartphone. To form a habit, I need to open it everyday.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Communication</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-01-communication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 15:06:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-01-communication/</guid><description>&lt;p>Communication is necessary in our life. Reading is also a form of communication. When I’m reading, it just like I’m talking with the author.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 12 Repetition</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-25-ep-12-repetition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 12:24:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-25-ep-12-repetition/</guid><description>&lt;p>Repetition is an essential part in our life.&lt;br>
Life is started from one cell. But just by copying itself, one cell can grow into a complicate system with different features. It’s a form of repetition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we need to memorize something, we aIso need a lot of repetitions. Maybe it’s very boring, but I can’t deny it’s a very effective way.&lt;br>
When we need to gain a skill, we also need a lot of repetitions. We usually started from a very basic practice. Only after enough times of practice, we can learn more advanced skill.&lt;br>
At first, even a basic skill is challenging to us, After enough repetition, it will become more and more easier. Then based on this skill there can growing more advanced skills.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cash</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-18-cash/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 15:24:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-18-cash/</guid><description>&lt;p>I bought a wallet and started using cash again recently.&lt;br>
It’s a very interesting try. I’ve been getting used to pay by smartphone for many years. It’s feeling weird after suddenly giving up E-pay. But now I found that I can still be relaxed when I going out without smartphone.&lt;br>
When I was paying, the feeling of “touching money” is very authentic. Compare with just tapping on the phone, I prefer the feeling of real money.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 11 Pure writing</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-11-ep-11-pure-writing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 13:39:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-11-ep-11-pure-writing/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-anchor-fm-inc wp-block-embed-anchor-fm-inc">
&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Writing is a essential part in the life of thinking and learning. It’s also indispensible for me.&lt;br>
But the way of writing has changed a lot. Writing on paper is the most traditional way.&lt;br>
I can still vaguely remember the days when I was writing journal on paper under the dim light of lamp. I enjoyed the feeling of writing on paper.&lt;br>
But it’s very inconvenient to write on paper. We can’t take all of our notebooks easily. It’s also difficult to look up former words.&lt;br>
I started writing on note-taking apps in 2016. It’s really convenient and solved the former problems.&lt;br>
There are a lot of features on noke-taking apps. We can change the style and font of notes. We can insert images, audios, even attachments of any format…&lt;br>
But in recent years I realized I spent so much time on the features of the software. It created a lot of difficulties to saving and sharing. Another problem is that, note-taking app is installed on electronic devices. Phones and computers contains more features and notifcations. Now I think this way of writing also has its negative effect. It will create a lot of distractions.&lt;br>
Recently I started writing in plain text. I can write in any note-taking softwares. Using special device for writing is also a good idea.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Switched to Windows</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-04-switched-to-windows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 14:39:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-04-switched-to-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don’t need to be too stubborn and stick to the Linux. Tools are used for improving efficiency instead of for playing. Some ideas are not so that important.&lt;br>
Windows is very powerful now especially after the coming of Android Subsystem. On Linux, I can’t find a similar software as stable as Subsystem. Waydroid and Genymotion have a lot of problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 10 Temporary guest</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-27-ep-10-temporary-guest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 15:49:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-27-ep-10-temporary-guest/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I was organizing my contact information. I found a lot of people I haven’t contacted in a long time. As time goes by, they disappear from my life and never reappear. It’s as if they died even though I have their information. Each of them is like a temporary guest. I don’t know if there will be a chance for us to meet in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m gradually able to start a new relationship. But at the moment I still don’t have the ability to reconnect with old people, but I’m trying my best. I feel that many people don’t have this ability because of embarrassment. We just let these relationships die one by one. I don’t want to be isolated, so to avoid that situation, I also have to overcome my fear.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cashflow E-Game</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-20-cashflow-e-game/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 14:05:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-20-cashflow-e-game/</guid><description>&lt;p>Based on the recommendation from Rich Dad’s book, I try to install the Cashflow game. But the desktop version of E-Game is difficult to install now. I tried my best to install it successfully in VirtualBox.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the past few months, I have been playing the Cashflow 101 e-game. I have gradually become proficient at it. It’s very educational and I’ve gained some knowledge about cash. These days I started to try Cashflow 202. It’s more complicated compared to the 101 edition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 9 Technical breakdown</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-13-ep-9-technical-breakdown/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 14:52:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-13-ep-9-technical-breakdown/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I went through a serious problem of my server, on which my website runs.&lt;br>
It started with the problem of the version of PHP. The edition of the current PHP is very old and it couldn’t support the running of some plugins. Then I tried to install a new version of PHP, but it didn’t work. When I tried to uninstall the old version, the server crashed and could not be restarted due to an error called “kernel panic”.&lt;br>
I’ve done my best to fix it myself until midnight. It’s useless. I could only ask other people for help. The technical staff couldn’t solve it either, but they helped me to backup the data. It’s a very tedious experience and I could restore my server after several days. Finally, I used the backup data and restored my website.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twenty books</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-08-twenty-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:52:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-08-twenty-books/</guid><description>&lt;p>Until today I finished reading 20 books written in English.&lt;br>
Twenty books is not a lot, but it’s a big step for me.&lt;br>
It’s a good accomplishment.&lt;br>
Just keep going.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 8 Real wealth</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-30-ep-8-real-wealth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 15:07:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-30-ep-8-real-wealth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wealth is usually considered to be money. But in my opinion, true wealth does not only contain money. It can contain many things, such as health, wisdom, and experience.&lt;br>
An essential part of wealth is health. We inherited our health from our ancestors when we were born. It’s innate and priceless. But we can partially change it. We can destroy health, but we can also increase it.&lt;br>
Another part of wealth is wisdom. Although our health can be inherited, we can’t inherit wisdom. Through learning, reading, and education, we can gradually get wisdom. Everyone has their own wisdom. It’s also priceless in different people’s lives.&lt;br>
Finally, experience is also a part of wealth. Good experience is wealth, and bad experience is a kind of debt. But whether it is good or bad, whether it is a wealth or a liability, all depends on how you look at yourself. Everybody has unique experiences. If we can get more experience, we might be able to handle challenges more easily in the future.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Complicate physical activities</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-23-complicate-physical-activities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 15:02:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-23-complicate-physical-activities/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my opinion, simple physical activities are not enough to improve mental health.&lt;br>
As human beings, we get used to coordinate with our mind and body. Repeated and easy activities are boring. If the activities are more complicated, it’s better for our mentality. We can also combine different activities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 7 Practice</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-16-ep-7-practice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 17:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-16-ep-7-practice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Practice is one of the most important things in our life.&lt;br>
In order to gain our skill or improve our ability, we all need to have enough practice.&lt;br>
Practice is repeated action. Enough times of repetition is necessary in our life. If we do a lot of practice, we will definitely get some improvements unconsciously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In most cases, the beginning of the practice is very difficult. We think it’s hard, it’s a big challenge. We may have tried many times, but there are still no results at all. We want to give up. But if we continue and persevere, as the times of practice increase, our improvement will be faster and faster. This is a phenomenon that shows up in many areas. The problem is that we give up so easily.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loop Habits Tracker</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-09-loop-habits-tracker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 15:09:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-09-loop-habits-tracker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maybe I can use plain text instead of software to track my habits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 6 Plain text</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-02-ep-6-plain-text/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 15:03:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-02-ep-6-plain-text/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have used a lot of software to store my notes and data. But gradually I found that although these softwares are very convenient and they offer a lot of good services. They also caused me a lot of trouble in the long run.&lt;br>
One important reason is that you cannot export your data freely. I tried a lot of softwares after I decided to write online. Many of them don’t provide good export service. Your files can only be exported to some special formats. What’s more, these files can only be viewed in some special forms. We can probably convert them to other formats we want, but it’s not that easy.&lt;br>
Another reason is that I realized that some tools and services could give you a lot of convenience and unique features, but when you get used to it. You are also limited by these tools. Your choice would be less, and it’s also very inconvenient if you want to change your tool. Especially for a person who is always curious about new tools. Technology is a double-edged sword. I always want to find a suitable tool for writing, learning, productivity, etc. But the result is not so good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automated system</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-24-automated-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 14:03:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-24-automated-system/</guid><description>&lt;p>Creating an effective and automated system is very important.&lt;br>
I always look at the tools. But any tools should be built on a good system. Tools are medium. I must know how to use these tools.&lt;br>
With an effective and stable system, you don’t even need a tool with high technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 5 Thirteen years of journaling</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-18-ep-5-thirteen-years-of-journaling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 09:52:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-18-ep-5-thirteen-years-of-journaling/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been journaling for thirteen years.&lt;br>
I started journaling in April 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s one of the most important habits in my life.&lt;br>
Before 2016, I wrote journals on paper. After 2016, I started to write on app. It’s very convenient to write digitally. After December 2017, I started writing in English.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I became aware that journals are the history of my own life.&lt;br>
Now I have the intention to collect all my journals and publish them in a book. I think it would be very interesting to browse through my whole life.&lt;br>
Looking back to my childhood, I realized that I already have the talent to collect the materials in different periods and save them in order. I enjoyed that kind of feeling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reading the first five books of the Bible</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-11-reading-the-first-five-books-of-the-bible/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 09:55:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-11-reading-the-first-five-books-of-the-bible/</guid><description>&lt;p>After almost a year of intermittent reading, I have finally finished the first five books of the Old Testament. The first five books are also called the books of Moses.&lt;br>
I suddenly realized that probably seventy percent of the Bible is the Old Testament. Only a small part of it is the New Testament. The Old Testament is written in Hebrew, and the New Testament is written in Greek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are some stories that impressed me a lot. Killing and punishment may be the theme during the time of Moses. There is a city called Sodom, which is a city that indulges in lust and sin. People run away before Yahweh destroys this city completely. But the people who turned their heads and looked back at Sodom, still became pillars of salt.&lt;br>
Moses and the generation of Israel living in Egypt ran away from it, all could not see the land promised by God. Only they all died, later generations can start the journey and see the land.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 4 AI tool for learning</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-04-ep-4-ai-tool-for-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 20:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-04-ep-4-ai-tool-for-learning/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m Qiran. Today, I would like to share with you my understanding of Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I gradually realized that AI has already entered my life. Some people may think that AI is very destructive to the lives of ordinary people. But in my opinion, the most distinct characteristic that humans possess and surpass other creatures is the ability to use tools. AI is a very useful tool now, and it would be highly beneficial if we can learn to use it effectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stickers</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-28-stickers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 11:18:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-28-stickers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Why do I no longer use stickers? For me, the use of stickers distorts the understanding of others. I don’t think it’s an effective or appropriate way to communicate with others online. The Internet is already full of entertaining and useless information. Using stickers will make this situation worse. Using words is enough to convey accurate information. Although without stickers, some people will think that it will feel that there is no emotion. But the truth is that the Internet cannot emulate the real conversation. Calling and talking face to face may be a better way for communication.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 3 Feel the fear</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-21-ep-3-feel-the-fear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 11:34:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-21-ep-3-feel-the-fear/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi, I’m Qiran. Today I would like to share with you my understanding of fear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fear is one of the basic human emotions. We all have fears. As for me, fear is one of my biggest difficulties in life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are different kinds of fear.&lt;br>
The first fear of myself is the fear of being disappointed by others. In terms of human relationships, I’m really an infant now. I am afraid of falling.&lt;br>
I always avoid dealing with others, just like an infant avoids learning to walk. But if I never fall down, I cannot learn to walk forever.&lt;br>
I knew I had to accept disappointments. Maybe I’m able to collect them in order to develop my abilities. I don’t have to take them personally. Disappointments are actually assets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why don’t lie</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-14-why-dont-lie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 23:06:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-14-why-dont-lie/</guid><description>&lt;p>When we were kids, elders always tell us not to lie. But most of us lie because we are afraid of the consequences after telling the truths. As a child, lying is a good protection. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s always a bad habit to lie to yourself or to other people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lying can distort our understanding of reality. When we lie to ourselves, at first we think we can avoid the difficulties or solve some problems. But we will gradually lose the ability to face the real world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP 2 The tree of habits</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-07-ep-2-the-tree-of-habits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 03:37:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-07-ep-2-the-tree-of-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi, I’m Qiran. Today I would like to share with you some of my understanding about habits.&lt;br>
In my life, the concept of cultivating habits is gradually becoming one of the most important parts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my opinion, habit is a compound interest. The fruits or effects of habits will grow faster and faster in the long run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me, one of the examples of daily habit is writing journals. Maybe it’s my longest habit, which started from my middle school time. Now it has become my important habit that records my life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change the title</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-28-change-the-title/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 12:53:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-28-change-the-title/</guid><description>&lt;p>Changed the title of the English website.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EP-01 Why I start my podcast</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-21-ep-01-why-i-start-my-podcast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 15:47:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-21-ep-01-why-i-start-my-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello everyone. I’m Qiran. This is the first episode of my podcast. Today’s topic is that, I want to share reasons about why I start my podcast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first reason is, it’s a place of sharing my thoughts and my understanding covering a lot of topics. It’s an opportunity to exchange ideas with others, maybe I can meet new friends and learn a lot from others in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second, I think I can cover a lot of topics that I’m interested in. Forcing myself to write something is a good habit to learn, and it’ll also help me improve my thinking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1: EP-01 Why I start my podcast</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-21-1-ep-01-why-i-start-my-podcast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 07:29:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-21-1-ep-01-why-i-start-my-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;!--[if lt IE 9]>&lt;![endif]-->&lt;audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-4600-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%;" controls="controls">&lt;source type="audio/mpeg" src="https://anchor.fm/s/db2d53e4/podcast/play/65408337/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2023-1-21%2F31aaec7e-c25d-72f6-6051-835f196df83e.m4a?_=1" />
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://anchor.fm/s/db2d53e4/podcast/play/65408337/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2023-1-21%2F31aaec7e-c25d-72f6-6051-835f196df83e.m4a">https://anchor.fm/s/db2d53e4/podcast/play/65408337/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2023-1-21%2F31aaec7e-c25d-72f6-6051-835f196df83e.m4a&lt;/a>&lt;/audio>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hello everyone. I’m Qiran. This is the first episode of my podcast. Today’s topic is that, I want to share reasons about why I start my podcast.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reading list</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/reading-list/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 15:35:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/reading-list/</guid><description>&lt;p>The books I have finished reading:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>No.&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Title&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Author&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Date of completion&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Rating&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Atomic Habits: Tiny Changes, Remarkable Results&lt;/td>
&lt;td>James Clear&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2021&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Hobbit&lt;/td>
&lt;td>J.R.R Tolkien&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2021&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Gods at War&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Kyle Idleman&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Almanack of Naval Ravikant: A Guide to Wealth and Happiness&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>On Regular Investing&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Xiaolai Li&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Rich Dad Door Dad&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Robert Kiyosaki&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>7&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Animal Farm&lt;/td>
&lt;td>George Orwell&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>8&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Shallows&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Nicholas Carr&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>9&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Effortless English: Learn To Speak English Like A Native&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A.J. Hoge&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★☆☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>10&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Carnivore Diet&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Shawn Baker&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>11&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Learn Enough HTML, CSS and Layout to Be Dangerous&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>12&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Learn Enough JavaScript to be Dangerous&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>13&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Rich Dad’s Cashflow Quadrant&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Robert T. Kiyosaki&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>14&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Richest Man in Bablylon&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Charles Conrad&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★☆☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>15&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Rich Dad’s Before You Quit Your Job&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Robert T. Kiyosaki&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★☆☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>16&lt;/td>
&lt;td>No More Mr. Nice Guy&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dr. Robert A. Glover&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>17&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Prince&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Machiavelli&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2022&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★☆☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>18&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Practice Makes Perfect English Grammar for ESL Learners&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Ed Swick&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>19&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Complete Idiot’s Guide to the TOEFL&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>20&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Mere Christianity&lt;/td>
&lt;td>C. S. Lewis&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>21&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Rich Dad’s Guide to Investing&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Robert T. Kiyosaki&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★☆☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>22&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The 250 Sales Questions to Close The Deal&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Stephan Schiffman&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★☆☆☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>23&lt;/td>
&lt;td>How to Have Confidence and Power in Dealing With People&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Leslie T. Giblin&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★☆☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>24&lt;/td>
&lt;td>What To Say When You Talk To Self&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dr. Shad Helmstetter&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>25&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Road Less Traveled&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Peck, M. Scott&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>26&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Sex Is Not the Problem&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Joshua harris&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>27&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Becoming Human&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Jean Vanier&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023-08&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>28&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Sales Dogs&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Blair Singer&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023-09-11&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>29&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Courage to Be Disliked&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Fumitake Koga; Ichiro Kishimi&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023-10-15&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>30&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Critical Thinking Concepts and Tools&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Richard Paul; Linda Elder&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023-10-17&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>31&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Sexual Detox&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Tim Challies&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023-11-04&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>32&lt;/td>
&lt;td>American Accent Training&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Ann Cook&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023-11-17&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>33&lt;/td>
&lt;td>How to Develop Self-Confidence and Influence People by Public Speaking&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dale Carnegie&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2023-12-23&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>34&lt;/td>
&lt;td>How to Enjoy Your Life and Your Job&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dale Carnegie&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2024-01-22&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>35&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Selected Stories by O.Henry&lt;/td>
&lt;td>O.Henry&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2024-01-27&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★☆☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>36&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Linux in easy steps, illustrated using Linux Mint&lt;/td>
&lt;td>McGrath, Mike&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2024-02-29&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★☆☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>37&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Unlocking German with Paul Noble&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Paul Noble&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2024-03-04&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>38&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Money Blog&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Nathaniel Branes&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2024-03-27&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>39&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Easyway to Stop Smoking&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Allen Carr&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2024-04-14&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★★☆&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>40&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Why We Get Sick&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Benjamin Bikman&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2024-05-31&lt;/td>
&lt;td>★★★⁠★⁠★&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>It’s updated from time to time…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reply to Chris</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-08-reply-to-chris/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 12:31:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-08-reply-to-chris/</guid><description>&lt;p>Chris:&lt;br>
I definitely know Austria.&lt;br>
You can find out more about me on my personal website. By the way, why not leave a footprint there?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s great that you’re interested in learning a language. It’s a long way for learning something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, it is. I’m Qiran. Nice to meet you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Qiran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Share</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-08-4299-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 12:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-08-4299-2/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter">
&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">
i cannot believe this is actually real &lt;a href="https://t.co/zo9pl0bXjU">pic.twitter.com/zo9pl0bXjU&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>&amp;mdash; delian (@zebulgar)
&lt;pre>&lt;code>&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/zebulgar/status/1620436085376712705?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;quot;&amp;gt;January 31, 2023&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Update home page</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-08-update-home-page/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 11:17:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-08-update-home-page/</guid><description>&lt;p>Added progress bars and more social icons for home page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Added the feature which can share posts on Mastodon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Z-library in Nov. 2022</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2022-11-04-z-library-in-nov-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 02:49:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2022-11-04-z-library-in-nov-2022/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter">
&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
&lt;p lang="zh" dir="ltr">
完蛋了，全世界最大的电子图书馆被 ban 。&lt;br />&lt;br />全世界最大的电子图书馆 z-lib 被美国警方查封，目前官方所有网址均无法访问。&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/zlibrary?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#zlibrary&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://t.co/AyebO3xbK8">pic.twitter.com/AyebO3xbK8&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>&amp;mdash; Bruce 小胡同学 𝕏 (@huhexian)
&lt;pre>&lt;code>&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/huhexian/status/1588350395818311680?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;quot;&amp;gt;November 4, 2022&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>Z-library&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="">&lt;/a>The official URL of Z-library is down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can still access it on the dark web for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The URL is: &lt;a href="http://zlibrary24tuxziyiyfr7zd46ytefdqbqd2axkmxm4o5374ptpc52fad.onion/">http://zlibrary24tuxziyiyfr7zd46ytefdqbqd2axkmxm4o5374ptpc52fad.onion/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can access it using Tor Browser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UPDATE: You can access it. but you cannot download book files directly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can log in an account and tap “send to Email” , then you will receive the book file from your Emailbox.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Separation</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2022-08-04-separation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 15:37:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2022-08-04-separation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Totally separated my blog into two subsites– English site and Chinese site. It’s more convenient for viewers to choose their familiar language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Added the language switcher menu.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mastodon</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2021-02-20-mastodon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 02:29:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2021-02-20-mastodon/</guid><description>&lt;p>Removed some plugins from my blog. &lt;s>Added options for foreign languages&lt;/s>.&lt;br>
Added the Mastodon icon and removed the YouTube icon.&lt;br>
Tried out Mastodon, a decentralized social networking software. I think it is a good alternative to Twitter.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5 Love Languages</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-11-27-introduction-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 13:32:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-11-27-introduction-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-happens-to-love-after-the-wedding">What happens to love after the wedding?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Like languages in linguistic, there are also 5 languages in love. If we cannot understand the love in other’s love language, we cannot communicate love.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="keeping-the-love-tank-full">Keeping the love tank full&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We all have a love tank from our childhood.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="falling-in-love">Falling in love&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It’s a illusion. The average in-love experience lasts two years.&lt;br>
The in-love experience is not our own growth. It’s a sense that we arrived.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Your Habits Shape Your Identity (and Vice Versa)</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-11-11-how-your-habits-shape-your-identity-and-vice-versa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 01:44:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-11-11-how-your-habits-shape-your-identity-and-vice-versa/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are three layers: outcomes; process; identity.&lt;br>
Identity is the deepest.&lt;br>
“I’m not a smoker” is better than “I don’t smoke.”&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
&lt;p>
The system of a dictatorship has a very different set of beliefs like absolute authority and strict obedience. You can imagine many ways to try to get more people to vote in a democracy, but such behavior change would never get off the ground in a dictatorship. That’s not the identity of the system. Voting is a behavior that is impossible under a certain set of beliefs.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction and Chapter 1</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-11-10-introduction-and-chapter-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 06:54:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-11-10-introduction-and-chapter-1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="introduction-my-story">Introduction: My Story&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The writer shared the exprience when he was in high school. He was hit by a baseball bat.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-fundamentals-why-tiny-changes-make-a-big-difference">THE FUNDAMENTALS Why Tiny Changes Make a Big Difference&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-surprising-power-of-atomic-habits">The Surprising Power of Atomic Habits&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>You can start as a small win.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
&lt;p>
Habits are the compound interest. Your habits can compound for you or against you.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Positive Compounding&lt;/strong>: Productivity compounds; knowledge compounds; relationship compounds.&lt;br />&lt;strong>Nagative compounding&lt;/strong>: Stress compounds; negative thoughts compound; outrage compounds.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ARGUMENT THREE: SOCIAL MEDIA IS MAKING YOU INTO AN ASSHOLE</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-10-31-argument-three-social-media-is-making-you-into-an-asshole-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 14:56:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-10-31-argument-three-social-media-is-making-you-into-an-asshole-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SOOTY SNOW&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
You are more vulnerable when you get addicted.&lt;br>
You will become a poor or little snowflake.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>MEETING MY INNER TROLL&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The author said BUMMER causes two extremes, be an asshole or be very careful.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>THE MYSTERIOUS NATURE OF ASSHOLE AMPLIFICATION TECHNOLOGY&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
we need to be solitary wolves rather than wolves in packs. When we are in the pack, we cannot think individuality, but in a group cult.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>THE MOST MASTERFUL MASTER SWITCH&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Rather than Facebook or Twitter, LinkedIn built a high environment because there is no reason to catch your attention.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>GO TO WHERE YOU ARE KINDEST&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Don’t let your character degrade. When you latch on a platform, you always get irritable.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>When people are fake, everything becomes fake&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
You can’t even know who is real people.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>BUMMER kills&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
BUMMER made people believe fake things. Some people don’t believe vaccines, then once-defeated diseases revived.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 5-6</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-10-01-chapter-5-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 02:50:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-10-01-chapter-5-6/</guid><description>&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-toltec-path-to-freedom">The Toltec path to freedom&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Awareness, transformation and intent are three masteries that lead people to become Toltecs.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Death is a angel&lt;/strong>, teaches us live everyday as if it is the last day of our lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-new-dream">The New Dream&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Heaven on Earth&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
I WANT YOU TO FORGET EVERYTHING YOU HAVE. Use our imagination, and your emotions to dream heaven.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Prayers&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
We can be a prayer for love, a prayer for freedom.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join the Attention Resistance</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-09-23-join-the-attention-resistance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 06:16:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-09-23-join-the-attention-resistance/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>DAVID AND GOLIATH 2.0&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Use your attention intentionally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PRACTICE: DELETE SOCIAL MEDIA FROM YOUR PHONE&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
It actually forces you to approach them with more intention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Practice: Use Social media like a professional&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Like Jennifer, we need to use Twitter as a professional.&lt;br>
Do not surfing it endlessly, just check some accounts you need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PRACTICE: EMBRACE SLOW MEDIA&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
“low information diet”: Eliminating what’s bad aggressively than celebrating what’s good.&lt;br>
The writer suspect the European focus on slowness is more likely to succeed in the long run.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Delete “like”</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-09-23-delete-like/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 05:41:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-09-23-delete-like/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reference: &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.liuqiran.com/2020/08/12/dont-click-like/">Don’t Click “Like”&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 1-4</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-09-16-chapter-1-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 05:49:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-09-16-chapter-1-4/</guid><description>&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="chapter-1">Chapter 1&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>True justice is paying only once for each mistake. True injustice is paying more than once for each mistake.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-first-agreement">The first agreement&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Be impeccable with your word.&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Self-rejection is the biggest sin.&lt;br>
&lt;em>You can live in heaven in the middle of thousands of people living in hell because you are immune to that hell.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-second-agreement">The second agreement&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Don’t take anything personally.&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;em>If you don’t take the emotional poison, it becomes even worse in the sender, but not in you.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ancient Greece</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-09-08-ancient-greece/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 12:49:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-09-08-ancient-greece/</guid><description>&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="architecture-and-architectural-sculpture">Architecture and Architectural Sculpture&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Doric and Ionic orders.&lt;br>
&lt;em>Doric&lt;/em> formulated on the mainland; the &lt;em>Ionic&lt;/em> was the order of choice in the Aegean Islans and coast of Asia Minor.&lt;br>
&lt;em>shaft&lt;/em> is the vertical channels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Basilica, Paestum&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The columns of the Temple of Hera are swelling at the middle of the shafts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Temple of Artemis, Corfu&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;em>The hideous Medusa and two panthers at the center of this early pediment served as temple gaurdians.&lt;/em>&lt;br>
It’s a hard task for Greek sculptor.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reclaim Leisure</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-08-27-reclaim-leisure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 12:54:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-08-27-reclaim-leisure/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Leisure and the good life&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
As Aristotle’s lead, joyful activities is a “source of inward joy”. We can call them high-quality leisure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Bennett principle&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
(FI 2.0 movement is that if you can radically reduce your living expenses, you gain two advantages– you save money at a much faster pace and you don’t have to save as much to become independent.)&lt;br>
When you gain FI at a young age, you gain much leisure hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don’t Click “Like”</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-08-12-dont-click-like/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 13:34:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-08-12-dont-click-like/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Practice: leave your phone at home&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Having your phone is not a crisis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Practice: Take long walks&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Walking is better than sedentary. “If you’re wearing headphones, you are not really walking.”&lt;br>
But the hardest part of this practice is making the time.&lt;br>
Broaden your definition of “good weather”! You can get big rewards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Practice: Write letter to yourself&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;em>It”s a simple and easy practice to to deploy, but it’s also inscredibly effective.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Lopsided Arms Race</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-07-27-a-lopsided-arms-race/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 03:46:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-07-27-a-lopsided-arms-race/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>WE DIDN’T SIGN UP FOR THIS&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Smartphones changed our life, but they changed us drastically and no one predicted that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>TOBACCO FARMERS IN T-SHIRTS&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Big tobacco companies emerged, and they are harming us more.&lt;br>
Internet addiction is also a big problem.&lt;br>
intermittent positive reinforcement: the unknown is always enticing. the drive for social approval&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="spend-time-alone">Spend time alone&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Solitude Deprivation&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
We need to be free from input from other thoughts.&lt;br>
We need solitude to thrive and make important desicions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Whether You Want It or Not…It’s Yours</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-07-27-whether-you-want-it-or-not-its-yours-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 03:18:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-07-27-whether-you-want-it-or-not-its-yours-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>THE TRUTH IS THAT YOU REALLY ARE IN CONTROL—IN TOTAL CONTROL. You are consciously or unconsciously choosing to be in that lousy job.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol class="wp-block-list">
&lt;li>
Taking responsibility means never blaming anyone else for anything you are being, doing, having, or feeling.
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
Taking responsibility means not blaming yourself.
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
Taking responsibility means being aware of where and when you are NOT taking responsibility so that you can eventually change.
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
Taking responsibility means handling the Chatterbox.
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
Taking responsibility means being aware of payoffs that keep you “stuck.” (Don&amp;#8217;t think &amp;#8220;if only&amp;#8221;)
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>From Pain to Power</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-06-23-from-pain-to-power/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 17:10:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-06-23-from-pain-to-power/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pain to power; Helplessness to choice; Depression to Energy; Paralysis to action;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a power of love yourself, power of good love.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>love and power go together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>pain+—–+——+power&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m powerful and I am loved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Action is very powerful!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don’t be too serious! (Don’t be as my dad)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I hope” is a pain. You are not a victim, you just need to say “I know”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are responsible for your faults, then you can avoid it the next time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Myth and Dream</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-06-20-myth-and-dream/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 08:19:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-06-20-myth-and-dream/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>By the sacrilege of the refusal of the rite, however, the individual cut himself as a unit off from the larger unit of the whole community&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The hero is the man of self-achieved submission, …only birth can conquer death&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>We shall come to the center of our own existence&lt;/em>&lt;br>
like the labyrinth, it’s a path of hero&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Music in high school</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-06-12-music-in-high-school/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-06-12-music-in-high-school/</guid><description>&lt;p>说实在话，现在网上的流行歌曲越来越“刺激”，什么生僻字、芒种，还有绿色，只是堆砌辞藻一点内涵都没有，00后和90后的差别应该已经很大了吧。&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio">&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>再次听到了许嵩的《半城烟沙》，回忆起了初中时光。&lt;br>
许嵩是我初中时期的喜欢的网络歌手。08年前后那个时期流行“网络歌手”这个词，许嵩应该算是网络歌手里面最出色的吧，歌写得好、词也写得很棒。&lt;br>
那时，这算是当时流行的网络歌曲了。&lt;br>
那时，我会打开音乐软件，为下载了他的歌曲而高兴半天。感受年轻学生所谓的与众不同。&lt;br>
这算是最早的“流行”吧。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>不知道什么时候开始，当时跟风听许嵩歌的人说“都已经听不下去了”，“听腻了”。好像再唱许嵩的歌，就是什么落伍的事情。&lt;br>
后来我已经不再关注什么歌曲流行了。&lt;br>
一下子十年就过去了，生活越来越浮躁，我想问，那些说许嵩歌“落伍”的同学们，你们在哪里呢？还会跟着00后哼歌吗？&lt;br>
同学说，许嵩是一个低调的人。&lt;br>
是啊，相比起当时“网络歌手”的他来说，他已经更加低调了，但还是有人默默喜欢他的音乐。&lt;br>
原来，我才是真正的“非主流”。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 5 Energy 埶篇第五</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-05-21-chapter-5-energy-%E5%9F%B6%E7%AF%87%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%94/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 05:57:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-05-21-chapter-5-energy-%E5%9F%B6%E7%AF%87%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%94/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>我之正使敵視之為奇我之奇使敵視之為正正亦為奇奇亦為正.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>凡戰者, 以正合, 以奇勝。&lt;/em>&lt;br>
In order to secure victory, indirect methods are also important.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>戰勢不過奇正, 奇正之變, 不勝窮也。&lt;/em>&lt;br>
There are unending series maneuvers derived from 奇 and 正. In a war, we can use so many ways. Why just always think about 正?&lt;br>
It’s hard for me to use Zheng, but Qi is also useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>勢如擴弯, 節如發機。&lt;/em>&lt;br>
In this sentence, 勢 equals energy. Release your energy as soon as possible when a war begins.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter V RIDDLES IN THE DARK</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-05-20-chapter-v-riddles-in-the-dark/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 05:48:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-05-20-chapter-v-riddles-in-the-dark/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bilbo met a Gollum. Gollum lived on a slimy island in the dark lake. Gollum can eat goblins, but he also likes riddle.&lt;br>
&lt;q>What have I got in my pocket?&lt;/q> This riddle is not fair for Gollum.&lt;br>
Bilbo got a ring! It’s Gollum’s birthday present! Bilbo Baggins, he is a thief!&lt;br>
Now the ring made Bilbo invisible. He escaped the cave from goblins!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction 1</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-05-13-introduction-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 01:52:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-05-13-introduction-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wang Ch’ung displays a liberalism unique. He thik the present is better than the past, same as Ge Hong.&lt;br>
Cao Cao, was a competent poet. Cao Pi, 典論論文&lt;br>
蕭統，he accounted for excluding the Classics and historical works from his anthology, because they were not pure literature.&lt;br>
徐陵，玉臺新詠&lt;br>
Cao Pi consider that Qi, is born with us, it cannot be changed by instruction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>陸機 文賦&lt;br>
&lt;em>All external vision and sound are suspended,&lt;/em> &lt;em>Perpetual thought itself gropes in time and space;&lt;/em> &lt;em>Then, the spirit at full gallop reaches the eight limits of the cosmos,&lt;/em> &lt;em>And the mind, self-buoyant, will ever soar to new unsurmountable heights.&lt;/em> Through arduous work, we can reach the artistic impulse.&lt;br>
Great Void, Profound Silence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 2</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-05-07-chapter-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 09:29:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-05-07-chapter-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>現在的問題已經從提高電梯服務轉移到了其他地方，老板抱怨、客戶也在抱怨。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHAPTER 4 Tactical Dispositions</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-04-25-chapter-4-tactical-dispositions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 13:25:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-04-25-chapter-4-tactical-dispositions/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>見勝不過思人之所知, 非善之善者也。&lt;/em>&lt;br>
Know the ken of the common herd is not enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>故善戰者, 立於不敗之地, 而不失敵之敗也。&lt;/em>&lt;br>
不失敵之敗 equals does not miss the moment for defeating the enemy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>是故勝兵先勝而後求戰&lt;/em>&lt;br>
We need to lay plans before the battle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>勝者之戰民也, 若決積水於千例之豁者, 形也。&lt;/em>&lt;br>
This kind of conquering force, it’s like the bursting of pent-up waters into a chasm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Connection</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-04-09-connection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 04:19:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-04-09-connection/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio">
&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
&lt;p>
Hold my hand&lt;br />I&amp;#8217;m real powerless to fight&lt;br />Can you lead me to the light?&lt;br />My strenght has come to fear&lt;br />Fled in truth of dawn&lt;br />Curious as a day&lt;br />My heart huh woah oh
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
&lt;p>
Can you bring me back to life?&lt;br />Ignite the fire again?&lt;br />Can you bring me back home where I am not alone?&lt;br />I&amp;#8217;m lost inside, the night and I cannot find you&lt;br />Bring me back
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Questions about Wenxin Diaolong</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-04-08-questions-about-wenxin-diaolong/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:17:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-04-08-questions-about-wenxin-diaolong/</guid><description>&lt;p>一、此文中如何理解“气”的美学意义？“气”这个概念为何对于艺术创作来说格外重要？&lt;br>
天地人的世界，不僅遵循著一致性原則，同樣也遵循類比性原則。它是一種主客互攝式的一體式的關係。“傍及萬品，动植皆文……”氣學的解释話語可涵蓋文學活动的各個方面。氣的這種自由出入、實象與虛境化合、包容萬有的質性十分契合藝術活动的本質特征。“神远”與“虛靜”开啓了客體與主體整體融和的一種境界，是中國式的意會體悟的言說方式。氣的一體兩面的特征貫通文學世界與形上世界。&lt;br>
造藝者的知、情、志、意的心理活动的整體性消融與化合，是需要借助于氣之關聯與貫通，纔可達致內外世界的和諧統一。“氣無奇類，文乏異采”、“氣偉而采奇”說明氣乃是構建文字、語言、辞采的前提。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>二、此文中讲到的刘勰“江山之助”论的思想内涵有哪些可能？他最后同意哪一种来源？&lt;br>
江山有抒發郁拂寥廓之氣，可直接詮释為貶謫。從根本上看，要在天、人之際達到平衡，不僅需要自然景物的陶冶，還要現實生活的感發，因此江山不等同於“山林皋壤”，而是指社会政治因素，這也是成就屈原《離騒》的更重要的內因。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2: Six dynasties</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-04-05-2-six-dynasties/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 13:08:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-04-05-2-six-dynasties/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="第一節-犍陀羅藝術與笈多藝術的東漸">第一節 犍陀羅藝術與笈多藝術的東漸&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>犍陀羅藝術&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
前期：貴霜王朝統治時期，約從公元1世紀初至3世紀中葉，以片巖石雕為主。&lt;br>
後期：薩珊王朝和寄多羅貴霜人統治時期，約從公元3世紀中葉-5世紀末，以泥塑為主。比前期更具古典主義氣質。&lt;br>
貴霜時代犍陀羅佛像開始打破印度早期佛教藝術的禁忌，遵循希臘、羅馬雕刻的慣例，仿照希臘、羅馬神像的樣品。&lt;br>
犍陀羅佛陀立像，2-3世紀，片巖，白沙瓦博物館。&lt;br>
犍陀羅佛陀坐像，2-3世紀，片巖，高73厘米，白沙瓦博物館。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>笈多藝術&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
樣式：馬圖拉和薩爾納特，代表印度古典主義最高成就。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>馬圖拉樣式&lt;/strong>：眉毛細長；眼簾低垂；鼻梁筆直，下唇寬厚，耳垂拉長呈矩形，頸部有三道折痕，被稱為“濕衣佛像”。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>薩爾納特樣式&lt;/strong>：比馬圖拉樣式更為單薄，幾乎像玻璃一樣完全透明，僅在領口、袖口和下擺邊緣依稀可見幾絲透明衣紋，被稱為“裸體佛像”。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>阿旃陀石窟&lt;/strong>：開鑿於公元前2世紀-7世紀。雕塑多屬裸體佛像，壁畫運用凹凸暈染法。&lt;br>
南印度阿馬拉瓦蒂：近似馬圖拉樣式。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>東漸的中介&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
康僧會：三國吳時期祖籍康居的僧人康僧會從交趾來到吳都建業（南京）“設像行道”。&lt;br>
法顯：東晉僧人法顯從長安出發西行求法，經鄯善、於闐而度蔥嶺，歷遊天竺諸國。&lt;br>
宋雲與比丘惠生：北魏孝明帝或胡太後詔遣使者宋雲與比丘惠生從洛陽出發使西域取經，經於闐至烏萇、犍陀羅諸國。&lt;br>
玄奘：玄奘從長安西行求法，經高昌、屈支（龜茲）至梵衍那（巴米揚）、犍陀羅等地。並在那爛陀寺留學5年。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>東漸中國西域&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
南北兩道：南道於闐等地系由犍陀羅中心地區通過克什米爾即迦濕彌羅（罽賓）傳入；北道龜茲等地系由巴米揚一線向東，或由罽賓北上經犍陀羅中心地區至迦畢試，再由迦畢試向東傳入。南道明顯受到犍陀羅藝術的影響。北道早期較多受到犍陀羅藝術和笈多藝術的影響，中期較多受到印度和波斯藝術的影響，晚期較多受到中國內地藝術的影響。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>鄯善&lt;/strong>：（樓蘭）佛像體現犍陀羅地區希臘化風格佛像的特征。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>於闐&lt;/strong>：呈現印度、波斯與中國因素混合的風格。&lt;strong>《合十禮拜的菩薩》&lt;/strong>：人物造型、服飾和色彩的印度風味異常濃厚。 &lt;strong>《龍女》&lt;/strong>： 佩戴的珠寶飾物尤其是三重串鈴的腰帶都屬於古代印度流行的樣式。勾勒身輪廓和細部的線條，類似中國的鐵線描。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>疏勒&lt;/strong>：在今喀什、巴楚一帶，是西域絲路北道的前站。&lt;strong>圖木休克佛陀坐像木雕&lt;/strong>：具有笈多薩爾納特樣式佛像特征。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>龜茲&lt;/strong>：佛教遺跡以石窟為主，其中克孜爾石窟規模最大。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>高昌&lt;/strong>：內地影響更為強烈。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>東漸中國內地&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>炳靈寺石窟&lt;/strong>：甘肅永靖炳靈寺石窟西秦時期的第169窟，屬於“涼州模式”的典型之一。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>曇曜五窟&lt;/strong>：攝取了犍陀羅佛像的造像傳統或笈多馬圖拉樣式佛像的衣紋表現手法。以三世佛為主，主佛異常高大。雲岡石窟的“平城模式”一再變化，出現了褒衣博帶式服裝和秀骨清像的造型。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>“曹衣出水”&lt;/strong>：是對當時中國西域與內地流行的吸收了印度笈多馬圖拉樣式佛像影響的一種佛像繪畫與雕塑的形容和總結。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>張僧繇&lt;/strong>：類似於阿旃陀壁畫中頻繁使用的凹凸暈染法 。尉遲乙僧和吳道子亦熟悉此法。如屍毗王本生圖。&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="第二節-東羅馬與薩珊波斯工藝品的輸入">第二節 東羅馬與薩珊波斯工藝品的輸入&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>公元363年中國和東羅馬帝國第一次使節往還。 中國境內的東羅馬遺物：&lt;strong>金幣&lt;/strong>和金幣仿制品、金銀器和玻璃器。&lt;br>
玻璃器：這些玻璃器皿都是由北方運來的羅馬制品。鴨嘴形玻璃水註。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>薩珊波斯工藝品的輸入&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
薩珊波斯工藝品對中國南北朝至隋唐時期的藝術和工藝產生重大影響。薩珊波斯藝術的生命超過了王朝存在的年代。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>薩珊銀幣&lt;/strong>：一種國際貨幣在當時流通於東歐、中亞，6世紀時甚至通用於中國河西地區。&lt;br>
出土地區大多位於中西交通要沖及其延長線上。 是中國和伊朗文化交流的物證。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>薩珊波斯金銀器&lt;/strong>：有海獸紋、蓮花紋、馴鹿紋等。錘揲技法被移用於瓷器。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>織錦&lt;/strong>：5世紀前後出現，多以聯珠圓圈分隔為各種花紋單元。&lt;br>
吐魯番是出土薩珊波斯風格織錦比較集中的地區。&lt;br>
織錦對隋唐絲織業產生了重大影響。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chinese conversion</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-04-03-chinese-conversion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 13:13:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-04-03-chinese-conversion/</guid><description>&lt;p>已開啓中文繁簡轉換和關键詞搜索轉換功能，感謝&lt;a href="https://wordpress.org/support/plugin/wp-chinese-conversion/reviews/">WP Chinese Conversion&lt;/a>插件作者。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHAPTER IV Over Hill and Under Hill</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-27-chapter-iv-over-hill-and-under-hill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 05:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-27-chapter-iv-over-hill-and-under-hill/</guid><description>&lt;p>“Why, O why did I ever leave my hobbit-hole!” said poor Mr. Baggins.&lt;br>
They were chased by Goblins. Bilbo wished that he can stay in his comfort zone, but things worse happened.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHAPTER III A Short Rest</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-11-chapter-iii-a-short-rest-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 10:39:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-11-chapter-iii-a-short-rest-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s a long and hard journey. They all knew the adventure full of dangers. They were no food, no water, caught in the rain. In the last, they had a rest in Elrond’s house.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHAPTER II Roast Mutton</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-11-chapter-ii-roast-mutton/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 10:33:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-11-chapter-ii-roast-mutton/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bilbo, as a burglar, wanted to see and steal some foods from trolls, but Bilbo Baggins and dwarves captured by trolls. In the end, they were saved by Gandalf.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHAPTER 6 Tell Them I Love (Some) Randomness</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-08-chapter-6-tell-them-i-love-some-randomness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 11:56:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-08-chapter-6-tell-them-i-love-some-randomness/</guid><description>&lt;p>When the variation comes, people will rush into the door.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>HUNGRY DONKEYS&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Equal distance between food and water makes donkey die of hunger or thirst.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Political Annealing&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The problem of the United States is the two-party system, you cannot randomize a party that doesn’t exist.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>The Second Step: Do (Small) Wars Save Lives?&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Maybe the small wars or some battles strengthen the country.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>What to Tell the Foreign Policy Makers&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Saudi Arabia and the US formed an alliance for stability, but it’s very dangerous in the long run. Royalties controlled the whole country, but this alliance strengthens the fundamentalism underground. Maybe the country will get into a more disastrous situation in the future.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>WHAT DO WE CALL HERE MODERNITY?&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
We are moving into a period of modernity of MBA, lobbyist, secularization, etc.&lt;br>
The taxman, fear of the boss, and separate the work and leisure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ARGUMENT TWO: QUITTING SOCIAL MEDIA IS THE MOST FINELY TARGETED WAY TO RESIST THE INSANITY OF OUR TIMES</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-07-argument-two-quitting-social-media-is-the-most-finely-targeted-way-to-resist-the-insanity-of-our-times/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 14:05:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-07-argument-two-quitting-social-media-is-the-most-finely-targeted-way-to-resist-the-insanity-of-our-times/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>THE BUMMER MACHINE&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The better analogy for social media is paint contains lead in a house.&lt;br>
BUMMER: “Behaviors of Users Modified, and Made into an Empire for Rent”&lt;br>
&lt;strong>THE PARTS THAT MAKE UP THE BUMMER MACHINE&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Ais for Attention Acquisition leading to Asshole supremacy: this makes people online all nasty.&lt;br>
B Information and data always being recorded.&lt;br>
The BUMMER machine also makes the tech giant stronger, and it also creates a fake world.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>THE PROBLEM IS LIMITED, SO WE CAN CONTAIN IT&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
BUMMER is the problem to avoid, we need to delete BUMMER accounts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHAPTER I: AN UNEXPECTED PARTY</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-07-chapter-i-an-unexpected-party/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 10:33:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-07-chapter-i-an-unexpected-party/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bilbo Baggins, the hobbit, met dwarves and the wizard Gandalf.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bilbo lives in his comfortable cave, it’s a fantastic, cozy zone. But the wizard choose him. What’s more, his Tookish mind in his heart pushes him to the beginning of the adventure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>XXVII. Style and Nature</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-07-xxvii-style-and-nature/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 10:25:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-07-xxvii-style-and-nature/</guid><description>&lt;p>The style and nature need to be fitted with each other, the outer and the inner realities always correspond.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Han dynasties</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-06-han-dynasties/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 13:11:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-06-han-dynasties/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="第一節-外來工藝品與佛教藝術的東傳">第一節 外來工藝品與佛教藝術的東傳&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>西漢時期對外交流：絲綢之路；可能的海上航道。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>將域外想象為神秘的超自然的世界&lt;/strong>，激發了社會對於域外物質與文化的興趣。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>民間與西域的交往最早開始於&lt;strong>先秦時期&lt;/strong>。&lt;br>
代表：&lt;strong>青銅錯金銀有翼神獸&lt;/strong>。（或許與中亞、中亞的格裏芬形象有關）&lt;br>
古代遊牧民族的遷徙對早期歐亞大陸的交流起到重要作用。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>來自域外的工藝品&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>器皿&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>銀盒&lt;/strong>：水滴紋凸瓣，公元前2世紀，廣州西漢南越王墓出土。采用錘揲工藝（可能來自古波斯），有的有青銅圈足和飾件。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>銀壺&lt;/strong>：青海大通上孫家寨乙區3號墓出土，漢末至魏晉初年，肩部以錯金工藝裝飾六朵花葉，從風格看有可能是中亞的產品。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>玻璃托盞&lt;/strong>：1-2世紀，廣西貴縣南鬥村出土，淺綠色，還有黃綠色玻璃瓶，均屬羅馬玻璃制品。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>紡織品&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>壁掛殘片&lt;/strong>：公元前2世紀-公元2世紀，新疆洛浦縣山普拉1號墓出土，上端人頭馬，下端執矛武士（可能是亞歷山大）。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>棉布殘片&lt;/strong>：1-2世紀，新疆民豐尼雅出土，白地印藍花，左下角有手持豐饒角的豐產女神德莫忒爾裸體半身像。（可能來自貴霜王朝的犍陀羅地區）&lt;br>
這些考古發現的工藝品，是漢代不同社會階層與域外交流的&lt;strong>見證&lt;/strong>。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>受外來文化影響的內地工藝品&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>玉角形杯&lt;/strong>：公元前2世紀，西漢南越王墓出土，可能源於西方的酒器“來通” 。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>鍍錫銀盒&lt;/strong>：前述外來的水滴紋凸瓣銀盒相似，被推定為仿制品。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>東漢胡人石雕&lt;/strong>：2世紀，山東青州出土。胡人石雕以四川、山東最為常見。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>佛教藝術的東傳&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>八角石柱&lt;/strong>：山東沂南北寨東漢墓，2世紀。兩尊帶項光的立像，與各種仙人和祥瑞並置。&lt;br>
佛塔上的相輪（窣堵波）和中國傳統樓閣的結合。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>四川樂山麻浩崖墓佛像&lt;/strong>：四川樂山麻浩東漢崖墓中的佛像，頭光、肉髻，著袈裟，結跏趺坐，具有佛像的典型特征。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>搖錢樹上的佛坐像&lt;/strong>：四川彭山東崖墓出土，2世紀，樹座上和樹身上的西王母的形象有時被替換為佛像。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>佛塔畫像磚&lt;/strong>：四川什邡白果村，東漢至蜀漢，樓閣上有剎桿、三重露盤、寶珠，是佛教觀念和神仙系統的樓閣建築對接的結果。&lt;br>
特別的文化現象：佛像作為道教偶像雜於道教藝術中。&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="第二節-漢代藝術在東方各國的傳播">第二節 漢代藝術在東方各國的傳播&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>越南東山時代&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
東山時代：公元前至公元二世紀，受中國戰國至漢代影響。&lt;br>
漢文化遺物：石斧、&lt;strong>青銅制作的鼓&lt;/strong>、玉質裝身具、&lt;strong>陶瓷&lt;/strong>、貨幣。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>東山銅鼓&lt;/strong>：&lt;br>
銅鼓紋樣：圓弧紋、鋸齒紋、飛鳥紋、船紋、蛙紋。&lt;br>
用途：用於呼喚靈魂的巫術祭儀、用於農耕儀式特別是乞求降雨或者象征著統治者的王權。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>河內出土陶瓷&lt;/strong>：酷似漢代的硬灰陶、也有施透明灰釉的灰釉陶。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>朝鮮樂浪時代&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
樂浪時代：公元前108至313年，屬中國統治範圍，中心為樂浪郡。&lt;br>
樂浪漢墓：在今平壤，有木槨、磚室兩種。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>樂浪漆器&lt;/strong>：保存於木槨墓中，器面多用紅、黃、綠三色，繪有人物、動物等。與長沙馬王堆漢墓漆器並稱為東方漆器雙壁。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>畫像磚&lt;/strong>：保存於磚室墓中，有神仙思想的動物紋，也有程式化的木口紋。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>日本彌生時代&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
彌生時代：東京彌生町發現以農耕文化為代表的陶器，下限為公元三百年頃。是伴隨水稻生產的銅石並用的文化。&lt;strong>銅鐸&lt;/strong>成為該期受中國影響最有代表性的藝術文物。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>銅鐸&lt;/strong>：出土於近畿和瀨戶內海沿線，可能是銅鐘和馬鐸的結合體。按大小分為大中小三種。&lt;br>
銅鐸紋樣：橫帶紋、袈裟襷紋、流水紋、凸線帶紋。&lt;strong>顯示了該時代金屬工藝的巔峰。&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
銅鐸上的紋樣是該時代紋樣的集成，有的還是珍貴的繪畫。這些繪畫以鑄成的&lt;strong>凸線構成&lt;/strong>，通過&lt;strong>線條&lt;/strong>表現形象。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>日本古墳時代&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
古墳時代：公元3-6世紀，受漢墓影響出現封土高大的宏偉墳墓。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>銅鏡&lt;/strong>：&lt;br>
古墳出土的銅鏡類型：“舶入鏡”；“仿制鏡”；獨創意匠的“日式鏡”。&lt;br>
直弧紋鏡：直線和弧線的巧妙組合。&lt;br>
房屋紋鏡：寫實表現當時的四種民居。&lt;br>
狩獵紋鏡：描繪逐鹿獵手，構圖自由氣氛活躍。&lt;br>
和歌山八幡神社畫像鏡：古紋後期作品，表明日本這此時已能全部理解中國鏡的形式。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>“漢倭奴國王”金印&lt;/strong>是已知首次傳播到日本的漢字。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>銘文大刀&lt;/strong>：約438年，出土於熊本縣江田古墳。&lt;br>
刀背上刻制銘文並用銀鑲嵌，被認為是日本現存最早的在日本書寫的文字。&lt;br>
這種在金屬上銘刻的素樸文字，可以說是日本書法的萌芽。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ARGUMENT ONE: YOU ARE LOSING YOUR FREE WILL</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-04-argument-one-you-are-losing-your-free-will/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 05:50:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-04-argument-one-you-are-losing-your-free-will/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="welcome-to-the-cage-that-goes-everywhere-with-you">WELCOME TO THE CAGE THAT GOES EVERYWHERE WITH YOU&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We are remotely controlled like animals in cages. We even don’t know that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-mad-scientist-turns-out-to-care-about-the-dog-in-the-cage">THE MAD SCIENTIST TURNS OUT TO CARE ABOUT THE DOG IN THE CAGE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The silicon valley gradually realizes the problem, but we cannot wait for them to solve this problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="carrot-and-shtick">Carrot and shtick&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Not only the pleasing kind, but punishment can also play an important role in addiction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VI</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-03-vi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:24:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-03-vi/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fear becomes easier to master when our mind is diverted from the things feared to fear itself.&lt;br>
Unconscious and concentrate on the objects is perilous.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Practice digital drawing</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-29-practice-digital-drawing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 11:23:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-29-practice-digital-drawing/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="../uploads/2020/02/Project-4_2.jpg">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Are Emotions For?</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-28-what-are-emotions-for/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-28-what-are-emotions-for/</guid><description>&lt;p>From the story that a parent rescued their daughter and perished, we can learn that self-sacrifice is an irrational urge from emotion. Our emotion is an extraordinary power that guides us to handle the challenges of life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>WHEN PASSIONS OVERWHELM REASON&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
From the tragedy that happened in Crabtree, we can learn that passions always overwhelm ration time and again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Impulses to Action&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;em>In our emotional repertoire, each plays a unique role.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Read notes</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-28-read-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 10:20:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-28-read-notes/</guid><description>&lt;pre class="wp-block-preformatted">作者认为柏拉图对艺术的看法不妥。但在柏拉图的观点中，可以说艺术和他要建立的真理与乌托邦是对立的，本身就是有局限性的。柏拉图认为艺术应被禁止再现罪恶性情、放荡、粗鲁，是否也可以说柏拉图在批判摹仿性艺术满足人低劣的那一部分？&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>在古希腊中常有和欲望有关的故事，如对于古希腊神话中常有的身体幻化，我认为是很好的例子，如宙斯的幻化、阿波罗幻化成月桂树、牛头怪，人马兽也是其中之一，比如人马兽是国王伊克西翁被宙斯所塑造的涅斐勒所生，最终半人马被神所杀死。&lt;br>
喀戎是一个例外具有良好的品格，被徒弟赫拉克勒斯在追杀半人马强盗时误伤，喀戎本是不死之身，但赫拉克勒斯的箭浸泡了九头蛇的血，喀戎感到疼痛最终放弃永生换取普罗米修斯的自由。&lt;br>
半人马一般被当作野蛮，情欲，酗酒的代表，半人马被认为是酒神的追随者。人马可以表示着上半身、人的理性驾驭不了下半身的欲望？最终人马被神所杀死，喀戎也成为悲剧的代表，是否也意味着着这种野蛮、情欲的代名词，在古希腊中它最终要被神惩罚？半人马的故事对我们理解艺术尼采的酒神精神有什么启示？&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Plato and Aristotle</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-28-plato-and-aristotle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 10:17:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-28-plato-and-aristotle/</guid><description>&lt;p>柏拉图和亚历士多德艺术思想的比较：&lt;br>
柏拉图认为，艺术只是完美、永恒的本原的一种有缺陷的再模仿，人们从这种虚假模仿中是得不到真理（美）的；亚历士多德则肯定艺术家创作过程本身的作用，同时通过艺术作品对自然的模仿，人们更能深刻理解对象的美。&lt;br>
柏拉图认为，因为来自“灵感”、“礼物”，艺术是有力量的，同时也是危险的。为了保护理想的公民和理想的社会，艺术等级不高，必须严格控制；亚历士多德则认为艺术的模仿是一种教育和学习形式，是有价值的。&lt;br>
柏拉图认为，艺术家的灵感来源于神性的启发而不是一种技能，因此艺术家相比医药、建筑、算术等需要技巧的一类人更低级；亚历士多德则更为乐观，认为这种创造艺术的能力隐含在“模仿”之中，同样需要大量的学习和练习。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thinking aloud</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-26-thinking-aloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 02:08:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-26-thinking-aloud/</guid><description>&lt;p>Speak out your thinking, &lt;a href="https://www.lifehack.org/865493/cognitive-thinking">thinking aloud&lt;/a> can improve your cognitive thinking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>And the Clock Struck 8/8/08</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-15-and-the-clock-struck-8-8-08/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 15:12:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-15-and-the-clock-struck-8-8-08/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>I&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The author got in touch with a man who had a vasectomy. Zhu lost her only daughter, he full of regrets that he followed the rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>II&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
When the Olympics games approached, the government swung into build buildings like CCTV Underpants, Egg, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>III&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
When the count ran down, the author had a miscarriage, the game is over. During the time of the opening ceremony, there are a lot of rumors. The Chinese government can play the Small ball, but they don’t fare Big ball, the commercial and creative sports as well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>After the Quake</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-14-after-the-quake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 12:31:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-14-after-the-quake/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>I&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
After the quake, The parent lost their own child.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>II&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The place of the earthquake is a test case of the one-child policy. So many parents lost their own child in the earthquake in 2008. After the quake, the Communist party recede the propaganda of the policy but banned the news about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>III&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
This policy may be made China less productive, some people fired and lose their job because of this policy, it is crazy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHAPTER 5 The Souk and the Office Building</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-14-chapter-5-the-souk-and-the-office-building/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 12:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-14-chapter-5-the-souk-and-the-office-building/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>TWO TYPES OF PROFESSIONS&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
There are two types of professions, employee and taxi driver, though the first one has a high salary and stable, it’s fragile. This profession is in a system of artificial and human-made. But the second one is antifragile, same kind profession corporates artisan, prostitute, etc. Nature like small mistakes and variability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Lenin in Zurich&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Because Swiss have no government, it formed a bottom-up system that causes stability. There is no big idea that can generate in this country. It’s a magnet for ugly rich and tax refugees.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHAPTER 3 Attack By Strategem</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-11-chapter-3-attack-by-strategem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 12:54:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-11-chapter-3-attack-by-strategem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>故上兵伐謀, 其次伐交, 其次伐兵, 下政攻城&lt;/em>&lt;br>
Destroy the enemy’s plan is the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>攻城之法為不得已。修槽鎮輕、具器械、三月而後成&lt;/em>&lt;br>
During the war, we need a full preparation to besiege a walled city. It will spend a lot of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>將不勝其忿, 而儀附之&lt;/em>&lt;br>
The general may lose their patience before the engines of attacking prepared.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>拔人之城而非攻也, 人之國而非久也。&lt;/em>&lt;br>
Therefore, the skilled generals will overthrow their kingdom without any operations. They will not harm individuals but destroy the government. The typical instance is the Wu Wang, who put an end of the &lt;em>Yin&lt;/em> dynasty.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>THE PROCRASTINATOR IN YOUR LIFE</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-09-the-procrastinator-in-your-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 08:16:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-09-the-procrastinator-in-your-life/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="managing-people-who-procrastinate">MANAGING PEOPLE WHO PROCRASTINATE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Due to procrastination, employees lose their productivities and cause companies billions of dollars lost.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="commitment-vs-compliance">COMMITMENT VS. COMPLIANCE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>As a manager, you need to use inviting commitment rather than demands for compliance.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="focusing-on-starting-vs-finishing">FOCUSING ON STARTING VS. FINISHING&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Effective managers always have the ability to communicate with their employees. Focusing on starting is much more effective for a perfectionist.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="getting-results-or-giving-criticism">GETTING RESULTS OR GIVING CRITICISM&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>You need to give praise instead of criticism for employees. Praise even needs to precede the recommendations for improvement.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>State Your Priorities Clearly&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Don’t change your priority too often.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Be Decisive&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
You need to be decisive and don’t change the goal during the project. When you choose one, don’t change it.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Be Fair and Frequent in Your Rewards&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Craving to be appreciated is a deep need in human nature.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>LIVING WITH A PROCRASTINATOR&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Maybe you are living with a procrastinator, you didn’t need to put commands do them, just say I would instead of you should.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>A LAST WORD&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Go ahead! Don’t say I’ll try or it’s not working, just be open-minded and do it!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FINE-TUNING YOUR PROGRESS</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-08-fine-tuning-your-progress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 10:31:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-08-fine-tuning-your-progress/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>PLANNED SETBACKS&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
You can try to plan procrastination when you meet a big project, and record your self-statement, these statements may be your old pattern.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="resilience-and-hardiness">RESILIENCE AND HARDINESS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Resilience&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Resilience is very important when you fail, every time you fail you can bounce back from it and know your performance isn’t your self-worth, but your performance is connected to your perseverance. You don’t need to be responsible for what had happened to you, but you need to be responsible for how to tackle these problems. Sarah’s experience told us that you will meet some obstacles placed by others, but you don’t need to put these pressure on yourself, you just need to set a time for yourself and see how much you can finish.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Waging War</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-19-waging-war/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 16:02:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-19-waging-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>故兵聞拙速，未睹巧之久也。&lt;/em>&lt;br>
If you exposed a war too long, even you are ingenious, you will make a mistake. leave a little to your opponent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>力屈，財襌（殫），中原內需於家，百姓之費，十去其七&lt;/em>&lt;br>
Waging a war, you need to forage on your enemy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>故殺敵者, 怒也;取敵之利者, 貨也&lt;/em> Kill your enemy from the power generated by your anger, get benefits from your foe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WORKING IN THE FLOW STATE</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-18-working-in-the-flow-state/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-18-working-in-the-flow-state/</guid><description>&lt;p>Being into the state of flow is beneficial to your mental and physical health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>USING MORE OF YOUR BRAIN&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Using your left side of your brain is important, you need to shift into a state of flow. You need to stop your linear thought.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>IT’S ONLY YOUR FIRST DRAFT&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Creativity is important, how to get into it? You need to suspend criticism and linear thought and get into the state of flow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Curator and exhibition</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-10-curator-and-exhibition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 05:51:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-10-curator-and-exhibition/</guid><description>&lt;p>Curator 是一个专有名称，曾经被作为“博物馆馆长”之意。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>做一个策展人要具备资金筹措能力。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>故宫的展览负责人以前是一个机构，以前很稳定。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>从展览体制上日本的博物馆和西方没有区别，学艺员的背景是艺术史和博物馆学。 近20年当代形态的艺术开始进入博物馆。 以现当代艺术命名的博物馆开始出现。（美国惠特尼博物馆）&lt;/p>
&lt;p>从策展人到独立策展人体现能力的提升可以把各种资源有效的进行组合。&lt;br>
他不涉及到卖作品，画廊和策展人没关系。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>如果要想做一个和它相关的展览是不是具备可能性，很多当代艺术的展览模式可能就是需要展览空间。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>他们能敏感的发现社会当中的一个动向。泽曼先生被当成最早的独立策展人。&lt;br>
策展人在很大程度上是思维的先知者。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Kills Me Makes Others Stronger</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-10-what-kills-me-makes-others-stronger/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 05:33:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-10-what-kills-me-makes-others-stronger/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="antifragility-by-layers">Antifragility by layers&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Some parts on the inside of a system may be required to be fragile in order to make the system antifragile as a result.&lt;/em> All restaurants are combating with each other in order to form the antifragility of the whole group. If a single restaurant is too robust when the crisis happens, all reasons are boil down to the fragile of this restaurant.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="evolution-and-unpredictability">Evolution and Unpredictability&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Nature (and nature-like systems) likes diversity between organisms rather than diversity within an immortal organism…&lt;/em>&lt;br>
Evolutions benefits from the randomness but the unit died from the harms.&lt;br>
So I need to build some new systems different than the habit system, such as an energy managing system or log system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>THE ODES OF ZHOU AND THE SOUTH</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-09-the-odes-of-zhou-and-the-south/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 01:56:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-09-the-odes-of-zhou-and-the-south/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>葛覃  GE TAN&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
刈yì 濩huò 絺xī 綌yì 斁yì 薄污wù我私&lt;br>
Why does she want to go back to her home? Maybe her life is very hard, though she was hardworking, she didn’t get any respects. In this chapter, I think this woman was from a high ranking family, not like the propaganda from the government. Even though she is elite, but she also gets distresses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>卷耳    JUAN ER&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
寘zhì彼周行háng 陟彼崔嵬wéi 我馬虺huī隤tuí 我姑酌彼兕sì觥gōng 陟彼砠jū矣 我馬瘏tú矣 我僕痡fū矣&lt;br>
From 金罍, 兕觥, 僕, We can recognize she was from a rich family, the luxurious thing can not solve the problems about emotion, it’s also hard to hold a relationship.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alone</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-25-alone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 12:28:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-25-alone/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio">
&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I’m so alone, nothing feels like home.&lt;br>
I’m so alone, try to find my way back home to you&lt;/em>.&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio">&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Tainted Blood</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-20-tainted-blood/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 08:23:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-20-tainted-blood/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this chapter, the author introduced the families of Mi-ran and Jun-sang, Mi-ran’s father is a warrior from South Korea and he was captive by North army, he was forced to be a miner in Chojin (that town in northeastern), but he never told this to his daughters and son, until this tainted blood effects their life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jun-sang’s family is from Japan, they are wealthy as Japanese-Korean. when Korea divided, some Japanese-Korean thought the North government is better than South as a group battled with Japanese, so they went to North, but after the regime formed, they noticed everything changed, Kim Il-sung, never believe them, they were purged because God Kim didn’t allow them to be wealthier than common North Korea people and to connect their relatives in Japan. They couldn’t go back to Japan forever.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chinese modern art history notes 1</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-18-chinese-morden-art-history-notes-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 02:02:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-18-chinese-morden-art-history-notes-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>《点石斋画报》&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
编者：由吴友如主编，主要作者有吴友如，田子琳，金蟾香，周慕桥。&lt;br>
特点：配合新闻；注重时事；图文互释&lt;br>
表现形式：追求传统技法，汲取明清时期木刻版画艺术特点，同时采纳西洋绘画透视和人物解剖的特点，新颖活泼，时代气息强。&lt;br>
评价：是中国近代史上最早的画报，1884-1898年前后刊出15年，被认为是“中国近百年很好的‘画史’”。&lt;br>
标志：开启了图文并茂因而可能雅俗共赏的“画报体式，是传播新知识的途径，又是体现平民趣味的场所；&lt;br>
揭露：满清封建政权的腐朽统治&lt;br>
反映：《点石斋画报》所刊4000多幅美术作品，以民主求实的精神，反映19世纪末叶列强侵华史实和中国人民抵御外侮的卓绝斗争；反映科学技术的进步和人民对美好生活的渴望与追求。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>《真相画报》&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
介绍：由二高创办，1912-1913出版17期。&lt;br>
宗旨：监督共和政治，调查民生状态，奖进社会主义，输入世界智识。&lt;br>
目的：反对袁世凯，利用写真手法揭露时局真相，震慑反动政敌真实纪录时事新闻。&lt;br>
手段：直接或间接地以艺术为革命服务，艺术借力于政治宣传。&lt;br>
参与者：选登过曹华、黄宾虹、吴昌硕、王震、倪田等人的作品。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>李叔同&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
评价：是传播西洋美术的启蒙者。&lt;br>
1905年：官费赴日本留学，到东京上野国立美术专门学校。&lt;br>
1910年：归国，在天津直隶模范工业学堂任教。&lt;br>
1918年：出家。&lt;br>
受到印象派影响。&lt;br>
擅长油画、水彩、图案装饰。&lt;br>
代表作：《半裸女像》和留学时期的《自画像》&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>上海美专&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
创办：1912年由刘海粟、乌始光、汪亚尘创办。&lt;br>
评价：是现代意义上的第一座美术学校。改变了传统的师徒传承制，引进西方教育理念与机制。掀开了中国现代教育史上的第一页。&lt;br>
首创：男女同校；裸体女模特写生；大规模的旅行野外写生；中国第一本专业性《美术》杂志。&lt;br>
教学：借鉴日本和西方艺术教育，共有中国画科、西洋画科、工艺图案科、雕塑科等六科。&lt;br>
聘请：张大千、黄宾虹、潘天寿、陈抱一、关良等任教。&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="蔡元培及其在美术教育新艺术运动方面的贡献">&lt;strong>蔡元培及其在美术教育、新艺术运动方面的贡献&lt;/strong>*&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>蔡元培&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
投身：19世纪初蔡元培积极投身政治运动，对于中国现代教育、包括美术教育的发展也作出了巨大的贡献。&lt;br>
经历：历任：南洋公学教习、中国教育会会长、南京临时政府教育总长、北京大学校长、中央研究院院长等职。留学：1908年留学德国，接受了西方哲学、美学和教育学的影响，康德关于“美的超越性与普遍性”的理论观点对他产生了深刻的影响。成立：成立中华教育改进社、推动成立北京美术学校、发起成立北大画法研究会、担任上海美专校董。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>美术教育方面的贡献&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
强调：美术教育的重要作用，主张通过教育、尤其是审美教育来改变国民的素质，促使社会变革的实现。&lt;br>
代宗教：作“美育代宗教说”的演讲，宗教的出现和传播乃由于人们精神的需要，艺术的发生和发展也是人们精神需要的结果。&lt;br>
不忘：他在《文化运动不要忘了美育》中认为建筑、器具、广告等，都是美术家的意匠，人人都有时刻接触美术的机会。&lt;br>
规划：他在《美育实施办法》从胎儿美育到社会美育都作了详细具体的规划。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>新艺术运动方面的贡献&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
实践：蔡元培努力将自己的新艺术运动思想付诸实践，推动新式美术学校的成立。&lt;br>
奖励：奖掖后进不遗余力，促成徐悲鸿、刘海粟刘开渠、陈士文等美术青年赴海外留学。&lt;br>
主张：美术在变革社会的运动当中担当重要的任务，坚持艺术的精神作用，强调艺术的“非功利”特点。&lt;br>
认为：“外人能进步如此的，在以外，更赖美术。”&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="中国近代美术教育发生的变化">中国近代美术教育发生的变化&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>新兴美术教育&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
转机：中国近代美术教育史上的一大转机，莫过于新美术教育的崛起。&lt;br>
画馆画家：上海开埠后的土山湾画馆和官办美术机构还远远享受不了建立了中国近代美术教育摇篮的美誉。广东西洋画家群相比之下诞生了更多的画家。&lt;br>
学堂：李瑞清创办的两江优级学堂是清廷废科举之后的新创举；李叔同人体写生。&lt;br>
周湘：1910年周湘开办的图画函授学校是私人创办美术学校的先声。&lt;br>
上海美专：*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>美育思想建立与新艺术运动&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
蔡元培：*&lt;br>
颜文樑：*&lt;br>
林风眠：*&lt;br>
决澜社：*&lt;br>
全国美展：1929年由蔡元培力倡举办的全国美展成为中国新艺术运动的第二道冲击波。&lt;br>
二徐之争：*是第一次全国美展引起的中国现代美术思想的争鸣，他们各自都是站在当时中国的现状高度进行很有学术价值和中国现代美术史意义的探讨。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>筚路蓝缕&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
左翼美术家联盟：*&lt;br>
鲁迅和木刻版画：*到抗战时成为“美术救国的中坚力量。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Museum and public</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-17-museum-and-public/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 09:32:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-17-museum-and-public/</guid><description>&lt;p>公众态度公众责任如何建立？&lt;br>
很多民间的组织开始带领公众参观博物馆。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>我们可以从社会端参与到其中。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>一、当代社会语境下的博物馆下的博物与公众&lt;br>
博物馆与公众关系紧密与否，关系到博物馆的成熟度。&lt;br>
近20年来，多数博物馆开始制订积极的&lt;strong>公众战略&lt;/strong>。&lt;br>
如果纳稅人的钱并未投入到想要的地方。&lt;br>
理想的地方是纳稅人的钱可以投入到他理想的地方。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>在政府财政危机的时候博物馆应该规避风险。&lt;br>
“博物馆独立运动”&lt;br>
博物馆的服务方面打开后就开始市场化运动。&lt;br>
如何让它们之间的关系健康化。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>二、博物馆与公众关系的良性循环&lt;br>
关于“内向型”和“外向型”的博物馆的态度：&lt;br>
我们不要批判旧博物馆学，而是要让旧博物馆学变成新博物馆学。&lt;br>
组碍：公众与博物馆文化上的格阂。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>引发的问题的思考：&lt;br>
1、应当由谁来决定博物馆展出什么？（专业/非）&lt;br>
公众往往会有非专业的需求。&lt;br>
2、社会大众的兴趣和需求是怎样确定的，博物馆应如何对比作出反应？&lt;br>
很多的当代的艺术展是小朋友喜欢的&lt;br>
3、在满足大众需求中如何看待日益增长的多民族和多元文化问题。&lt;br>
这是任何一个博物馆应该关注的问题。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>798出现的多元文化的画廊&lt;/p>
&lt;p>诠释的视野&lt;br>
它让人感受到是必要的&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Holding Hands in the Dark</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-16-holding-hands-in-the-dark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 05:16:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-16-holding-hands-in-the-dark/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a love story between two teenagers, Mi-ran and Jun-Sang, although it happened in the most totalitarian country in the world–North Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mi-ran is a girl, her father is a miner, Jun-Sang is a student belongs to a family at a high level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the 1990s, the country’s economy broke down, and there is not enough electric power to keep the night be lighten, but the night in North Korea, it’s more natural and beautiful than other countries, no noises, no neons. What’s more, no one can spy the two teenagers, holding hands in the dark.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>THE MONEY TRAP: THE OLD ROAD MAP FOR MONEY</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-13-the-money-trap-the-old-road-map-for-money/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 09:17:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-13-the-money-trap-the-old-road-map-for-money/</guid><description>&lt;p>We seem like we don’t work for a living but work for dying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We need to think about how to see our jobs, in this world, we have a caste system of job, we divide them from their salaries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In America, though most people make 6,000$ a month still not happy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It seems like we have no choice and just be in the corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Limits to Growth:&lt;/strong> We are in the corner of growth, we think growth is the truth, we think more is better, but nature is finite, though technology will help us, the government will help us, but we don’t think about the problems of ourself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Written Assignment #2</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-09-written-assignment-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:01:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-12-09-written-assignment-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Translation&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The Master said to Yan Yuan, “If I’m employed, I’ll show my talent; If not, I’ll hide my light under a bushel, only you and I have the ability to do it!”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zi Lu said, “If you lead troops, whom do you want to work with you?” &lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Master Said, “If someone attacks a tiger unarmed or crosses a river without a boat, and he died without any regret, I would not work with him. What I need definitely is someone who is careful and fond of making plans for success.”&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Cat and the Washing Machine</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-29-the-cat-and-the-washing-machine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 12:59:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-29-the-cat-and-the-washing-machine/</guid><description>&lt;p>organic and mechanical are different, organisms are antifragile, also for human-beings. But in modern society, humans all live longer but weak, because the environment is so fragile. Unlike natural environment, their working environment, medicine and living quarters all making them weaker and weaker. Unlike mechanicals, organisms will become stronger because of self-repair in some point.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-complex">The Complex&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The man-made mechanicals are complicated but not complex, If you break them down, they don’t cause a ripple effect. But human society or ecology is complex, if you exterminate a specific animal, you will disrupt a food chain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Your Password Can Be Cracked!</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-29-your-password-can-be-cracked/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 11:55:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-29-your-password-can-be-cracked/</guid><description>&lt;p>Open the 2FA when it is possible, set a strong password (at least 25 digits).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction: Time to Disappear</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-27-introduction-time-to-disappear/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:43:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-27-introduction-time-to-disappear/</guid><description>&lt;p>We live in a world of low-privacy, and we also had an illusion about privacy, so many people said it’s not important to hide my privacy, so many people don’t care. but it’s a choice for yourself as for privacy, if you don’t care, your privacy may be going around the internet, maybe forever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This book will help you to learn how to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>encrypt and send a secure e-mail&lt;/li>
&lt;li>protect your data with good password management&lt;/li>
&lt;li>hide your true IP address from places you visit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>obscure your computer from being tracked&lt;/li>
&lt;li>defend your anonymity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>and much more&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Overcompensation and Overreaction Everywhere</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-27-overcompensation-and-overreaction-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 06:24:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-27-overcompensation-and-overreaction-everywhere/</guid><description>&lt;p>If as want to innovate and get creativities, we must get in trouble first, we cannot get invention from comfort.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-to-win-a-horse-race">HOW TO WIN A HORSE RACE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If we want to finish a task, we must finish it in our busiest time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="antifragile-responses-as-redundancy">Antifragile Responses as Redundancy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>the human’s kidney is a form of redundancy, it isn’t useless, because you can save for bad times. So it’s the same reason why we need to build strong will and get in trouble even though there is no hazard.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>6. THE UNSCHEDULE</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-24-6-the-unschedule/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 13:06:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-24-6-the-unschedule/</guid><description>&lt;p>When things start, we find the projects take less time than your thinking.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="even-producers-need-a-system">EVEN PRODUCERS NEED A SYSTEM&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This system is recording your time in the period of working, record every time in your period, you will reduce your fear about your so-called threatening subject.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="reverse-psychology">&lt;strong>REVERSE PSYCHOLOGY&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If you restrict your time of the study, you may have an aversion about it, you want to break the authority for yourself, and you will find you will increase your time of the study. So, set a rule of your working time, like “don’t work more than four hours a day”, you’ll find you want to work more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Brief Overview of 19th Century English</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-04-a-brief-overview-of-19th-century-english/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 12:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-04-a-brief-overview-of-19th-century-english/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google Books Ngram Viewer&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Ngram&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Commonly called an Ngram&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistical analysis of text or speech&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finds n(a number) of a certain item in  text (examples of n: phonemes, prefixes,  phrases, or letters)&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Google Books Ngram Viewer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
analyzed text (‘corpus’): books scanned  by Google&lt;br>
default time period: 1800 to 2000 output: graph representing use of  searched item in books through time (used in this presentation to show general  trends of increase or decrease of usage  from the 19th c.)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="historical-background-lohr">Historical Background (Lohr)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p class="has-text-color has-dark-gray-color">
Old English (Anglo-Saxon): &lt;strong>5th ­-11th&lt;/strong> centuries&lt;br />Since c. 450 CE, West Germanic peoples&amp;nbsp; settle southern Britain
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5: Education in Public Fine Art Schools</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-30-5-education-in-public-fine-art-schools/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 11:19:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-30-5-education-in-public-fine-art-schools/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="蔡元培与美术教育">蔡元培与美术教育&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>蔡元培在留学期间，康德“美的超越性与普遍性”的理念对他产生了深远影响。&lt;br>
1916年辞去教育总长职务&lt;br>
1917年：做“美育代宗教说”演讲&lt;br>
他认为美术在变革社会中具有重要的作用。&lt;br>
&lt;strong>向北洋政府建议开办美术学校&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
担任北大校长期间发起成立北大画法研究会&lt;br>
蔡元培极力支持林凤眠执掌国立北京艺术学校&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="从北京美术学校到国立北平艺术专科学校">从北京美术学校到国立北平艺术专科学校&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>五四新文化运动的“美育”思潮推动了美术教育的发展，使得美术教育脱离了实业教育的阶段。&lt;br>
1918年：国立北京美术学校成立，郑锦任校长&lt;br>
1921年：改称北京美术专门学校&lt;br>
1925年：增设音乐、戏剧二系，改称北京艺术专门学校&lt;br>
1927年：奉系时期改称为京师大学美术专门部&lt;br>
林凤眠聘请齐白石任教&lt;br>
1934年：教育部令恢复国立北平艺术专科学校&lt;br>
1937年：全面抗战爆发，学校南迁&lt;figure class="wp-block-image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="../uploads/2019/10/Screenshot_20191028_204634.png"> &lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>在林风眠的组织下，1927年5月1日，北京艺专师生联合社会的进步艺术社团组织了艺术大会，美术系举办美术展览，共展览了2000余幅作品，这些作品多抨击社会、讽刺现实。&lt;br>
事后，林风眠发表《致全国艺术界书》，指出没有国内真正创造的艺术品（模特儿事件），后林风眠被迫辞职。&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="国立杭州艺术专科学校-与林风眠的美术教育活动">国立杭州艺术专科学校 与林风眠的美术教育活动&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>1927年，国民政府定都南京，为改变当时国内艺术教育萎靡不振的情况下，蔡元培倡议设立国民艺术教育委员会，同年，在委员会议上通过“筹建国立艺术大学”提案。由林风眠、林文铮、王代之负责建校。&lt;br>
1929年：国立艺术院举行开学典礼。&lt;figure class="wp-block-image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="../uploads/2019/10/Screenshot_20191029_210304.png"> &lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1929年秋，学校改名为国立杭州艺术专科学校&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4: Emergence of Private Fine Art Schools</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-28-4-emergence-of-private-fine-art-schools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 11:52:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-28-4-emergence-of-private-fine-art-schools/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="第一节-上海美专与刘海粟的美术教育活动">第一节 上海美专与刘海粟的美术教育活动&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>早期上海美专的美术教育&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>周湘&lt;/strong>是开风气之先的人物&lt;br>
1911年：私人美术学校（布景画传习所）&lt;br>
1912年：西法绘像补习科&lt;br>
培养的人才：照相布景画-舞台布景画-肖像绘制&lt;br>
弟子：王师子，杨清磐，丁悚，张眉荪&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1912年底：刘海粟创办私人美术学校 （校长乌始光）&lt;br>
1915年：正式定名为上海图画美术院&lt;br>
1920年：上海美术学校&lt;br>
1921年：上海美术专门学校&lt;br>
1930：上海美术专科学校&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1913：举办画展&lt;br>
1918：《美术》创刊。&lt;br>
1919：学校教师组成天马会；邀请日本画家石井柏亭讲学；组建校董会，有蔡元培、梁启超、王一亭等知名人士&lt;br>
1923：学校建立艺术协会，建立《艺术》周刊；潘天寿任中国画系教师。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>刘海粟与“ 模特儿斗争”&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1914年：李叔同在浙江省立第一师范第一次使用人体写生（模特）教学&lt;br>
1915年：上海图画美术院开设人体模特儿课程。起用15岁小男孩做人体模特&lt;br>
1917年：举办暑期成绩展，陈列人体习作素描，引发社会反响。&lt;br>
1919年：刘海粟和画友举办展览，工部局指令撤去几张人体油画。&lt;br>
1920年代：美术学校采用模特儿为社会所了解。&lt;br>
1924年：上海美专学生饶桂举江西南昌举办画展陈列人体素描遭江西警察厅禁止。刘海粟写信请求撤销原令。&lt;br>
在上海，商贩为获取商业利益常将春画称为“模特儿”。&lt;br>
1925年：江苏省教育会通过禁止模特的提案。刘海粟发信置辩，数天后江苏省教育会回信澄清所禁模特为市场托名的裸体画。此事件引起极大反响。&lt;br>
保守势力开始大张挞伐，上海市议员姜怀素在《申报》发文，严禁模特，严惩刘海粟，刘海粟发文驳斥；上海总商会会长、实业家朱葆三致信刘海粟，认为刘海粟蛊惑青年男女。&lt;br>
1926年4月15日：《申报》刊载“上海县长危道丰严禁美专裸体画”大字号标题，新一轮模特斗争到来。17日，《申报》刊载《刘海粟函请孙传芳 、 陈陶遗两长申斥危道丰》 。&lt;br>
6月10日，《新闻报》刊载孙传芳给刘海粟的信，孙认为美术学校缺少模特无伤大雅。刘海粟回信认为“学术之事非一人而定”。孙传芳恼羞成怒，发出“通辑”刘海粟密令。后因学校处于法租界内，法国总领事对刘进行保护而结束。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>抗战时期上海美专的美术教育&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1937年：上海租界沦为孤岛。&lt;br>
1939年：刘海粟赴南洋办画展筹款。&lt;br>
1942年：内迁浙江金华。&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="第二节-苏州美专与颜文樑的美术教育活动">第二节 苏州美专与颜文樑的美术教育活动&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>1919年：颜文梁与友人发起组织美术画赛会&lt;br>
1922年：颜文梁与友人在苏州开办暑期讲习班&lt;br>
1924年：学校定名为苏州美术学校&lt;br>
1928年：颜文梁赴法国留学，后入巴黎高等美术学校学习；编印校刊《沧浪美》。&lt;br>
1931年：颜文梁回国，将留学期间节省出来的费用购置复制的石膏像五百件，图书万余册。&lt;br>
1933年：校刊改名《艺浪》。&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="第三节-私立美术学校的美术教育">第三节 私立美术学校的美术教育&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>上海私立中华艺术大学（1925-1930）：由陈抱一、丁衍镛主持。&lt;br>
上海立达学园美术科（1925-1933）：由匡互生、丰子恺、朱光潜等人创办。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Letter 4</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-26-letter-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 07:41:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-26-letter-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>When human in the prayers, they always want to pretend to be honest to the god, but they don’t in their heart. they always pretend to stick with their purposes but they always forget when they fell in some trivial things and some messinesses in reality, this is evil’s work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pa Yih 13 analysis</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-21-pa-yih-13-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 06:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-21-pa-yih-13-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tranlation’s words&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>谓：Legge’s translation: “meaning”, Eno’s translation: “sense”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>媚：Legge: pay court to; Eno: appeal to; Lau: be obsequious to&lt;/p>
&lt;p>灶：Legge: furnance; Eno: the kitchen god; Lau: the kitchen stove&lt;/p>
&lt;p>奥： Legge: the south-west corner; Eno: the god of the dark corner; Lau: the south-west corner of the house&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Legge translated “问曰”into “asked, saying” . Comparing to “asked” (Eno’s translation) and “said” (Lau’s translation) , Legge translated both words. Wangsun Jia asked a question after “问曰”in this chapter, so it is also understandable if only translate “问曰”into “asked” or “said”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Letter 3</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-19-letter-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 12:40:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-19-letter-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Evil making us misunderstanding others, always focus on build some image of others but don’t really true. If we make things trouble, we fell into illusions more we put others to meet our illusions more, then we destroyed our relationship with family, friends.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Letter 2</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-19-letter-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 11:52:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-19-letter-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Evil making yourself always thinking about reality, always focus on small things, in reality, and you always focus on other’s flaws, you maybe don’t believe truths and gods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OVERCOMING BLOCKS TO ACTION</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-19-overcoming-blocks-to-action/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 10:55:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-19-overcoming-blocks-to-action/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>THREE MAJOR BLOCKS&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>fear of failure, fear of not finishing, terror of being overwhelmed, these are the three blocks to action, if you solved one of them, it will be quiker to solve all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>TOOL #1: THREE-DIMENSIONAL THINKING AND THE REVERSE CALENDAR&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You don’t need to start with no anxiety, maybe it is impossible, if you always thinking about the right time to start, or permit yourself to learning, thinking searching helf along the project, and tell yourself you should be finished, you cannot avoid overwhelming anxiety.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>The Reverse Calendar&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Reversing the calendar gives you control of this project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pa Yih 13 translations</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-12-pa-yih-13-translations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 11:16:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-12-pa-yih-13-translations/</guid><description>&lt;p>【十三章】【一節】王孫賈問曰、與其媚於奧、寧媚於竈、何謂也。【二節】子曰、不然、獲罪於天、無所禱也。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Legge’s translation:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chapter XIII. 1. Wang-sun Chia asked, saying, “What is the meaning of the saying, ‘It is better to pay court to the furnace than to the south-west corner?&amp;rsquo;”&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>The Master said, “Not so. He who offends against Heaven has none to whom he can pray.”&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Commentary: THAT THERE IS NO RESOURCE AGAINST THE CONSEQUENCES OF VILATING THE RIGHT. Kea is the great officer of Wei, and having the power of the state in his hands, insinuated Confucius that it would be for his advantage to pay court to him. The southwest corner was from the structure of ancient houses the cosiest nook, and the place of honour.&lt;br>
Choo He explains the proverb by reference to the customs of sacrifice.&lt;br>
The furnace was comparatively a mean place, but when the spirit of the furnace was sacrificed to, then the rank of the two places was changed for the time, and the proverb quoted was in vogue. But there does not seem much force in this explanation. The &lt;em>door&lt;/em>, or &lt;em>well&lt;/em>, or any other of the five things in the regular sacrifices, might take the place of the furnace.&lt;br>
2 Confucius’ reply was in a high tone. Choo He says, “Heaven means principle” But why should Heaven mean principle, if there were not in such a use of the term an instinctive recognition of a supreme government of intelligence and righteousness We find the term explained by “The lofty one who is on high”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Belonging</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-11-belonging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 06:04:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-11-belonging/</guid><description>&lt;p>The author thinks we cannot just live alone, we need to have a belonging, but maybe love other people is hurt other people’s freedom. What’s more, we think we are in a group or a community, we can feel we are superior than others. we all need help, but sometimes we always hide this and think we are better than others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to think we are superior to others, we build walls, make our group against other groups, prejudice cultivates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GUILT-FREE PLAY, QUALITY WORK</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-11-guilt-free-play-quality-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 04:07:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-11-guilt-free-play-quality-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you see your work insatiable and infinite, you fell into a negative mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>THE IMPORTANCE OF PLAY&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Play can make us more effective, more creative, producers have more time to play than procrastinators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We need to know that play is important, through recreation and playing we get creativity. So in order to improve efficiency we need to spend time to play. We need plan for some time to play, producers always living without stressing about don’t finish the project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Museology</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-08-new-museology/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 02:19:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-08-new-museology/</guid><description>&lt;p>学期最重要的问题：作为一个个体与这个事物的关系。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>新博物馆学视野下博物馆认知&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>《当卢浮宫遇见紫禁城》&lt;/p>
&lt;p>博物馆学的三次研究高潮发生于30、50、80年代&lt;/p>
&lt;p>30:世界范围内第一次研究高潮&lt;/p>
&lt;p>50:世界博物馆学研究出现第二次高潮，开始成为世界性的事业&lt;/p>
&lt;p>20世纪60年代初期，博物馆学的活动逐渐独立并且清晰起来，博物馆组织的分类开始基于功能加以区分。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>80年代中期，“新博物馆学”运动&lt;/p>
&lt;p>广阔的社会背景：20世纪70年代随着全球性的生态危机和社区主义的发展，人们开始思考，博物馆和社会到底是一个什么样的关系？&lt;/p>
&lt;p>新博物馆学 理论基础：除方法与技术外，还要懂政治学、社会学等多学科&lt;/p>
&lt;p>发展策略：观众需要为主，大众主义，专家参与&lt;/p>
&lt;p>展示手法：动态的，采用主题单元展示，内容侧重内在与未来，尽量让观众参与，注意娱乐与休闲，多种传播方式。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>人如果只是私密化存在的话，社会是难以进步的。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>新博物馆学对博物馆的多重认识：&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>博物馆可以是不同形式的空间：&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“飞地” 人类可以通过这块飞地领略人类文化遗产。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“圣地” 它有广阔的历史时刻的特征，与宗教有关联，我们赋予了它极其崇高的地位。“偶像意象”、“治疗的潜能”、“仪式化之所”。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>“市场主导产业”&lt;/strong> 文化场所应该成为市场主导的形态。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>“殖民化空间”&lt;/strong> “展览是有特权的舞台，展示着自我与‘他者’的意象。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>艺术博物馆：文化表征的特征空间&lt;/strong> 无论是避难所、诊所还是监狱等，均是权力和知识关系的体制化的表现。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>艺术博物馆并非艺术经典的简单承载体。每一种展品的定夺无不是建立在人的文化认知与判断之上的。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reply in Slowly</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-08-replay-in-slowly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 22:06:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-08-replay-in-slowly/</guid><description>&lt;p>I also feel lonely last week, but I walked out recently.&lt;br>
I’m sorry to hear that you didn’t live with your parents 🙁&lt;br>
I think maybe it’s the reason you still struggling against loneliness.&lt;br>
In the book ‘Becoming human’, belonging is very important, we need belongings.&lt;br>
I’m so sorry my language is not very well? but I’m willing to hear your stories, through words, I hope we can build a good friendship ?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Analects notes 1</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-06-analects-notes-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 08:33:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-10-06-analects-notes-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>力不足者，中道而废，今女画。&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>如何达到自己的目标？有时候并不是我们没有能力达到，而是我们总是在中途放弃了。我们在跌倒的时候不断的质疑自己，如果我们爬起了，再次起来，我们总有可能到达最终的目的地，而当我们放弃了，我们就真的会认为：我们没有能力去做了。我们不断编织这样的谎言去否定自己，最终我们将自己囚禁在谎言的牢笼中。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>子曰、不有祝鮀之佞、而有宋朝之美、難乎免於今之世矣。&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>今之世推崇口才与容貌。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3: Upsurge in Study Art Aboard and Fine Art Education in Early 20th Century</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-30-upsurge-in-study-art-aboard-and-fine-art-education-in-early-20th-century/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 10:37:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-30-upsurge-in-study-art-aboard-and-fine-art-education-in-early-20th-century/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>留学日本的中国学生与美术教育&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>西方文化进入近代中国后，也冲击着传统的教育制度，洋务运动时期清政府即派学生赴美留学。1905年，清政府废弃科举制度，延续千年的文人传统升迁之途就此废弃，留学海外、学习西方文化与知识便成为读书人新的目标。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>日本是学习西方成功的代表，文化语言生活习惯与中国相似，同时日本政府为学生提供种种便利，因此日本成为当时留学生首选的目的地之一。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1906年左右的10年间，赴日留学生达2万余人，许多人学成归国后推动了各地的美术教育，如早期的曾延年、李叔同，曾延年学成回到家乡四川，担任成都高等示范学校艺术教职。北京、江苏、四川为赴日留学大省，这些地区的新式教育发展得更加完备，同时很多学校直接仿照日本教学模式办学，开设西洋画科，也聘请日本教员任教习。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>留学日本的画家有，陈师曾、何香凝、高剑父、周湘、陈树人、陈抱一、张善噂、张大千、丰子恺、刘海粟等。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>留学欧美的中国学生与美术教育&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>关作霖为代表的外销画家是最早留学欧洲的画家，之后留学欧洲的还有李铁夫、周湘、李毅士等。随着新文化运动的兴起，在“民主”、“科学”思潮洗礼下，留学法欧成为风气，不少人半工半读，这一时期的代表有林凤眠、徐悲鸿等。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RSS Feed</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/rss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 09:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/rss/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="../index.xml">English Site &lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../zh/index.xml">Chinese Site&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Masochism, Culture, and History</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-22-masochism-culture-and-history/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-22-masochism-culture-and-history/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Self in history&lt;/strong>: Before the Renaissance, self is not appeared by the control of religion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free is tough</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-21-free-is-tough/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 12:22:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-21-free-is-tough/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I browsed many articles about free software, especially &lt;a href="https://tech.sina.cn/it/2014-05-27/detail-iavxeafs2072085.d.html?from=wap">this article&lt;/a>, Stallman is sort of extreme, why I always care about extremely security and privacy too?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m not an extreme person in any topic, I need to have my life and my own goal, but because of my personality, I stick to some thinking that makes me different from others, in the end, it doesn’t make me very happy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My dreams(like become a native speaker or improve my skill and knowledge reserve very fast) are building in the air, not in the reality, why I cannot enjoy the road?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Touched</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-18-touched/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 04:36:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-18-touched/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio">
&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Several days ago I searched some pieces of music on Youtube and listening. when I’m listening to this music and saw the comments below. I’m very touched and weeping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven’t &lt;g class="gr_ gr\_13 gr-alert gr\_spell gr\_inline\_cards gr\_run\_anim ContextualSpelling multiReplace" id="13" data-gr-id="13">weeped&lt;/g> for a long time, remember that the last weep was two years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I took a comment here:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
&lt;p>
RonhiMusic&lt;br /> 4 months ago&lt;br /> &amp;#8220;The loneliest people are the kindest, &lt;br /> the saddest people smile the brightest, &lt;br /> and the most damaged people are the wisest. &lt;br /> All because they don&amp;#8217;t wish to see others suffer&lt;br /> &lt;g class="gr_ gr_148 gr-alert gr_gramm gr_inline_cards gr_run_anim Grammar multiReplace" id="148" data-gr-id="148">like&lt;/g> they do.&amp;#8221; -Anonymous
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Waging war 2</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-18-waging-war-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 01:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-18-waging-war-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>If we need t raising a good army, we need a big cost, such as time, money, but when army needs to go to the war, we cannot be exposed in the war for too long.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HOW TO TALK TO YOURSELF</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-13-how-to-talk-to-yourself/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 07:17:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-13-how-to-talk-to-yourself/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="../uploads/2019/09/image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-have-tosmessages-of-stress">The “Have To’s”—Messages of Stress &lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We need to change the self-talk of ‘I have to’.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-shouldsmessages-of-depression">The “Should’s”—Messages of Depression &lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If we always said should, we will fell into depression because the ‘should’ corporate many negative minds like I don’t agree, I don’t have a bright future, I don’t like. So change the self-dialogue and make the should image to ‘choose’, you will have freedom.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-power-of-choice">THE POWER OF CHOICE &lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The author shares his experience of jumping, he changed his mind from ‘have to’ to “I choose to exit the plane safely” and “I don’t want to be kicked out of the plane” when he jumping for the first time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EGYPT UNDER THE PHARAOHS</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-13-egypt-under-the-pharaohs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 23:42:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-13-egypt-under-the-pharaohs/</guid><description>&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="predynastic-and-early-dynastic-periods">PREDYNASTIC AND EARLY DYNASTIC PERIODS&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="painting-and-sculpture">Painting and Sculpture&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="palette-of-king-narmer">PALETTE OF KING NARMER&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Narmer’s palette’s narration is the normal form in Egypt, the artist use registers to make the palette more orderly, the figures in the palette combining profile view and frontal view. The pharaoh is the biggest in the center.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="architecture">Architecture&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="mastabas">MASTABAS&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mastaba is the standard tomb type in early Egypt. It’s a rectangular brick or stone structure with sloping sides.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prologue: Managing your life as an integrated whole</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-12-prologue-managing-your-life-as-an-integrated-whole/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 08:57:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-09-12-prologue-managing-your-life-as-an-integrated-whole/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>The old road map&lt;/strong>: Our planet face a lot of problems since the Industry Revolution, seems like we are using the old road map from the 19th century as for money and our life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Creating a new road &lt;g class="gr_ gr\_5 gr-alert gr\_spell gr\_inline\_cards gr\_run\_anim ContextualSpelling ins-del multiReplace" id="5" data-gr-id="5">map&lt;/g>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;g class="gr_ gr\_5 gr-alert gr\_spell gr\_inline\_cards gr\_disable\_anim_appear ContextualSpelling ins-del multiReplace" id="5" data-gr-id="5">Thinking&lt;/g> in new ways&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Financially independent thinking&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The results of FI thinking. You will naturally go to FI intelligence. One outcome of FI intelligence is saving six months of &lt;g class="gr_ gr\_121 gr-alert gr\_spell gr\_inline\_cards gr\_run\_anim ContextualSpelling ins-del" id="121" data-gr-id="121">expences&lt;/g> in your bank account at least.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Painting for aunt</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-30-painting-for-aunt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 13:24:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-30-painting-for-aunt/</guid><description>&lt;p>These days I painting for aunt, making my painting more figurative is a cool thing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Self</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-30-self/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 02:17:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-30-self/</guid><description>&lt;p>High levels are abstract. People alway want to go higher level thinking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shifting to low levels has two benefits, the first is people can avoid the control of high levels, the second is, people escape from strong emotions like anxiety.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People usually change between high levels and low levels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Self-awareness can occurs at different levels, at low levels, like pain and movement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Self-worth is very important if they cannot justify their actions and feel progress for their goals, self-worth will be very low.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MESOPOTAMIA AND PERSIA</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-29-mesopotamia-and-persia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 05:27:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-29-mesopotamia-and-persia/</guid><description>&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sumer">Sumer&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Sumerians developed city-states and formed a white temple for rituals. Sumerians also produced great literature.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="inanna">INANNA&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>It is a female head make up with fragments of white marble.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="warka-vase">WARKA VASE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>It was the first work of pictorial narration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="eshnunna-statuettes">ESHNUNNA STATUETTES&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The oversized eyes of these statuettes depict that the worships for deities and the wakefulness to the connection between deities and them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="stele-of-the-vultures">STELE OF THE VULTURES &lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The steel shows the battle of Sumerian.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How We Procrastinate</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-29-how-we-procrastinate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 17:01:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-29-how-we-procrastinate/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="creating-safety-the-first-major-step-out-of-procrastination">CREATING SAFETY: THE FIRST MAJOR STEP OUT OF PROCRASTINATION &lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Imaging that we always transform the task to a board before ourself, we can perform well if this board is on the land, but if the board is suspended between two buildings 100 feet above the pavement, then we are fearful to pass it.What’s more, we always feel a fire behind ourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We always fell in self-criticism so we use procrastinate to put off tasks until the deadline. It’s a victim mentality that we think we have to, no we will.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loneliness</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-28-loneliness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 04:19:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-28-loneliness/</guid><description>&lt;p>The author got some experiences which saw so many disabilities, they full of loneliness, painful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A human being needs a companion, and we need truths and make our worlds or communities better.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="community-and-rigid-order">Community and Rigid Order&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This is a paradox between the desire to belong, to fit in a community and to serve the deepest mind for oneself, close to God and be freedom.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-weakness-of-a-child">The Weakness of a Child&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We all born with weakness, we need love from parents as we cannot survive without others help. So if we don’t get love from the outside world, we will feel lonely. A lonely child will construct protection to survive and close his heart, but a child who gets love will more open to the world. we all have a lonely child in our heart, a lonely child can make us survive but also can destruct us.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Between Damocles and Hydra</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-27-between-damocles-and-hydra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 16:59:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-27-between-damocles-and-hydra/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="half-of-life-has-no-name">HALF OF LIFE HAS NO NAME&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The opposite of fragile is not robust, half of our life has no name for.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="please-behead-me">PLEASE BEHEAD ME&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We need to become Hydra, the serpent-like creature, we need some doses of antifragility, otherwise the sword of Damocles will get you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="on-the-necessity-of-naming">On the Necessity of Naming&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In the history of human, so many names of colors didn’t created, but this doesn’t mean we cannot discern different colors. We are doing more than we think.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Swimming pool</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-26-swimming-pool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 12:35:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-26-swimming-pool/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night I had a dream that I heard some news about Song Qingling, then my dad fell into a swamp suddenly, the next scene, two girls had a battle in the dirty swimming pool but we can see the bottom of the pool.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prologue</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-16-antifragile-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 21:19:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-16-antifragile-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Formal education cannot bring discovery and progress, only aggressive risk can.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In modern times, so many people avoid fragility through the expences of others.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-antidote-to-the-black-swan">The Antidote to The Black Swan&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We are very thirsty for order, we should embrace the randomness so that we can become control order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When facing small probabilities, we often fail, so only when understanding it, then we will not fearful.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="robust-is-not-robust-enough">Robust Is Not Robust Enough&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mother Nature cannot predictable, though it runs well for 4 billion years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Neolithic Art</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-13-neolithic-art/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 15:55:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-13-neolithic-art/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="anatolia-and-mesopotamia">Anatolia and Mesopotamia&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The agriculture developed, many towns developed, so the&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="jericho">JERICHO&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Around 7000 BCE, they developed stone buildings to defend nomad, it’s a great achievement, and they used the skulls for rituals, also using plaster to restore the skull, and inlaid seashells as eyes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="ain-ghazal">Ain Ghazal&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>They remarked the beginning of monumental sculptures in Mesopotamia.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="çatal-höyük">ÇATAL HÖYÜK&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>It developed the depiction of the human body, the shape of the torso, not only the profile. It also has the first depiction of a setting devoid of both humans and animals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why We Procrastinate</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-13-why-we-procrastinate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 12:29:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-13-why-we-procrastinate/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think the reason I always want to text with others is that maybe I want a connection with others to replace my relatives, but I should fish or cut the bait between the connection with others (the emotion relationship build by my parents) or my self-development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The story of Dorothy shows that procrastination is the choice between the self-improvement and others jealousy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I need to unlearn the pattern that my tasks are associated with the mind that I am lazy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paleolithic Art</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-11-paleolithic-art/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 11:17:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-11-paleolithic-art/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="africa">Africa&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>What shall be my subject? -animals, but men are rare. They’re almost profiled because the only profile can show the essence.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="western-europe">Western Europe&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Paleolithic human-headed shows that the ivory figure is very important for the artist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nude woman shows fertility images. The intents of makers maybe the female form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ancient artists always painted statuette.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sculptors usually change the subject to keep the profile view and details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="art-in-the-old-stone-age">Art in the Old Stone Age&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The question is why painters want to paint in these cavern, some people believe that these bison can provide food for them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Observe my life</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-10-observe-my-life/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 12:01:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-10-observe-my-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>I should record my life to observe and analyze why I will do these things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reason I always want to chat online is that I want to connect with others but I don’t want to talk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free and Easy Wandering</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-02-free-and-easy-wandering/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 11:46:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-02-free-and-easy-wandering/</guid><description>&lt;p>Different types of creatures cannot understand each other. It’s because there are different factors affecting, such as longevity and the environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Xu You’s saying means name is the only guest of reality. We should think about whether we can fit it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which is useless in one place can be very useful in other places, like the cream.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Krita practice 2</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-01-krita-practice-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 13:29:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-01-krita-practice-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="../uploads/2019/08/manhua-girl-1.jpg">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic concepts 4</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-01-basic-concepts-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 09:25:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-01-basic-concepts-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Carving and Casting: Subtractive, and addictive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relief sculpture: some sculpture is very boldly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Art historian should learn in other disciplines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No one can be truly objective.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Socrate</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-01-socrate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 05:26:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-08-01-socrate/</guid><description>&lt;p>People should not act on the basis of opinion, but true knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“The unexamined life is not worth living” (Apology 38A).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s not by art, but by divine power.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic concept 3</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-27-basic-concept-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 09:29:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-27-basic-concept-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Texture reflects the material.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SPACE, MASS, and VOLUME&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perspective, Foreshortening Foreshortening is one form of perspective, Rubens use it, Egyptian artists don’t use it, neither is the correct.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Proportion, and Scale Proportion can be changed for some intention.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic concepts 2</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-23-basic-concepts-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:02:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-23-basic-concepts-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Who made it? From the personal style, art historian can attribute who made these art works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Who paid for it? Patrons always have a big influence when artists are commissioned. They can change subjects and style in an artwork, under these circumstances, personal style is not important. So it is necessary to know who paid for it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basic words for art historian:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Form and composition (not only two dimensions but also 3D)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Laying plans 1</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-18-laying-plans-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 08:18:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-18-laying-plans-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>sovereign should have moral law.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before the war, you should think about whether moral law is sit on your side, if not, you lose Heaven.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before the war, you should create the situation for success, and make the plan for better circumstances.&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="has-text-color has-primary-color">
兵者, 龍道也。
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All warfare is based on deception, so we should deceive both of our friends and enemies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your opponent is bad temper, irritate him. Observe your enemy, if they are in ease, make him not rest, if they are united, separate him.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Masochism and sadism</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-17-masochism-and-sadism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 06:39:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-17-masochism-and-sadism/</guid><description>&lt;p>In Freud’s theory, masochism is from sadism, another theory said that sadism and masochism are two faces of one coin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the recent study shows that maybe masochism is more fundamental. The number of Masochists are much more than sadists’.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The submissive partners are really in control during SM, because it is the submissive’s desire shapes the sex play.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Masochistic desires are much stronger than sadistic. But many submissive people cannot find a partner to dominate them because of the shortage. So What happens often is two masochists meet each other, one of them should take turns.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic concepts</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-17-basic-conceptions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 06:20:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-17-basic-conceptions/</guid><description>&lt;p>What is art history:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Art history aims to learn and find the history and development of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The questions art historians should ask:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How old is it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is it’s style?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My friends</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/my-friends/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 07:51:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/my-friends/</guid><description>&lt;p class="has-contrast-color has-primary-background-color has-text-color has-background">
 “If you have an idea and I have an idea, we exchange these ideas, then each of us will have two ideas.”
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.dylanwu.space/">Dylan Wu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://imzm.im">陈仓颉&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://yir.me">YIR&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fspark.me">FSpark&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://phenol-phthalein.info/">Broca-Phenol&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://springwood.me/">沉舟侧畔&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://bkryofu.xyz/">非科学のカッ�&amp;hellip;&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://pewae.com">大致&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://osmh.net">OSMH&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.huhexian.com">青山&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://dreamendy.com">Dreamendy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.cxwblog.com">梅塔特隆立方&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://blog.moekira.com">Kira&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://kqh.me">kqh&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.yanshihua.com/">Mars&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://minuo.me">minuo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ul class="wp-block-list">
&lt;li>
&lt;a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blog.xinshijiededa.men/" target="_blank">新世界的大门&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Return to dreamland</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-06-return-to-dreamland/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:21:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-07-06-return-to-dreamland/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube aligncenter wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio">
&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p class="has-background has-primary-background-color">
梦饮酒者，旦而哭泣；梦哭泣者，旦而田猎。方其梦也，不知其梦也。梦之中又占其梦焉，觉而后知其梦也。且有大觉而后知此其大梦也，而愚者自以为觉，窃窃然知之。君乎，牧乎，固哉！丘也与女，皆梦也；予谓女梦，亦梦也。是其言也，其名为吊诡。万世之后而一遇大圣，知其解者，是旦暮遇之也。
&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="has-text-color has-light-gray-color">
不能直接看成美学和艺术理论：动物也许会死，重要的是我们会死但我们没有意识到会死。如果我们按照以前的方式，去超越现象追求本能打手电筒，做不到的时候我们还作为本体在世界存在，把现象只看成现象，不再痛苦，（丢了现象，不是本质的东西）如果我们把喜怒哀乐看成现象，就不会完全束缚在一个固定的地方，我们不应该被它所欺骗，我们在一个日常的梦中，把梦当梦时会更真实一点。这里就出现了一种艺术形式，当我们有一天看见一个东西，假象会教育我们，我们的现象不是真的。因此，恰恰相反，我们尝试画是假的，生活是真的，但画教育我们更真实的东西。这不是虚幻的欢乐，用一种方式。告诉我们我们在生活里面扮演戏剧。戏剧家告诉你们你在日常生活中也是一个存在的方式。艺术不是人类的消遣：它是让我们反过来让我们更真实的东西。如果我们只是意识到现象是现象，保持距离，会感觉虚幻和绝望。&lt;br /> 我们必须在现象世界中入手 意识到自己是本体，作为本体，你和现象世界中本来就没有距离 。现象就是本体上开出的一朵花。我们意识到自己是本体，但要投身于现象的世界中。（美学笔记）
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>因此，“庄周梦蝶”、“人生如戏”可以用尼采的反理性主义与美学解释：我们做梦经常意识不到自己会做梦，有时会意识到，但我们最终是会醒的。会醒的梦和人生这个不会醒的梦哪个更高级？人生的梦更低级，这个梦的现象太真实我们做得太投入了，以至于我们意识不到这是场梦。 理性最终能认识的、关心的只是现象世界。用再精密的仪器不停的拆分现象，在现象中打转，用手电筒照亮用眼睛看都已经是观察现象，用苏格拉底的“理性”是不可能达到本体世界的，如果只是相信知识和理性，我们就离本体越来越远。 尼采认为戏剧中的悲剧是肯定人生的最高艺术，我们不能消极、放弃“现象”，去“苦修”。因为本体永远不能脱离现象而存在，我们无法认识到本体的我，但现象就是“本体上开出的一朵花”，我们可以“作为”本体而存在，去做这一场梦。就算人生是一场杯具，我们不仅作为观众来看戏，还要作为演员入戏。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Categorize my blog</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-06-23-categorize-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 02:26:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-06-23-categorize-my-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>The most important decision is &lt;a href="https://www.liuqiran.com/index.php/2019/05/22/category/">changing categories&lt;/a>. so I think it is also important to categorize my writings, I improved the classification of my categories in my blog. I can read and found my writing through multi-level categories, classify them and reflect efficiently. I also can discover everything I wrote before through categories, like time traveling, know myself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-06-10-1263/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 02:24:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-06-10-1263/</guid><description>&lt;p>第一章比较好&lt;/p>
&lt;p>阿拉伯数字点汉字是顿&lt;/p>
&lt;p>严格的按照专业写作的格式（学校也有格式）&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;s>贡布里希.艺术的故事.2013&lt;/s> 这绝对是错的&lt;/p>
&lt;p>标准的是（英）贡布里希：《艺术的故事》，北京：……出版社，2013年版，第xx页&lt;/p>
&lt;p>不写就全都不写，一定要统一&lt;/p>
&lt;p>图注不能有符号 作者不用写国籍&lt;/p>
&lt;p>35×67厘米&lt;/p>
&lt;p>扣题 逻辑性 长篇议论文&lt;/p>
&lt;p>论点 就要有点 每个分论点扣一级标题&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zizek</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-06-06-zizek/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 08:22:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-06-06-zizek/</guid><description>&lt;p>意识形态批评&lt;/p>
&lt;p>意识形态不是强加在我们上面的。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>走出意识形态是痛苦的，意识形态会使你看到真相。自由是痛苦的。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>幻想正是组成意识形态的重要材料。幻想提供了简单的解答。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>过去的纯粹的消费主义，现在变得非常狡猾。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>颠覆斯大林主义的独裁不仅仅在于嘲笑领袖，还要破坏得以存在的依据——“人民”。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tropic love</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-05-30-tropic-love/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 09:29:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-05-30-tropic-love/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio">
&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>不知道为什么，听到这个背景音乐会感觉到有点伤心？是宝座被夺去的那一刻吗？&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I remember the ocean, Memories die out so hard. We were traveling the mountains, just to find the loudest seas. We settled down by the fire, knowing we could aim higher, but we didn’t know that yet. So if you want something to hold on to, gotta find it first. But here I am.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‘Cause I’ve been laying under palm trees, waiting for the summer, knowing there’s nowhere to do. ‘Cause I am happy on this island, Wanna be my funland? I don’t ever want to leave, I’m in a tropic love.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lu Zhi</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-05-25-lu-zhi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 22:19:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-05-25-lu-zhi/</guid><description>&lt;p>吴门画派的文人画家都有着和文征明一样早年仕儒、晚年隐居不仕的经历，陆治也不例外。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>陆治与文征明的交往大约于嘉靖二年（1523年）开始，他同文征明一同交游，并创作了大量的游记作品，并学习文氏画风陆治还与陈淳、王毂祥等同门关系甚好。文征明和陆治虽然没有明确的师生关系，但是陆治的早期风格受到文的影响。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>陆治的《雪窗易见图》与文征明的《溪山深雪图》用笔节奏、留白十分相似。这种构图与笔法在王蒙的《具区林屋图》中也可以找到。可以推测出陆治从文征明的绘画风格探索到了王蒙的笔意。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>清钱杜《松壶画忆》中提到在文众多弟子中，“陆叔平得其奇峭”。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Category</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-05-22-category/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 13:26:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-05-22-category/</guid><description>&lt;p class="has-background has-primary-background-color">
The most important decision you&amp;#8217;ll ever make: Change your categories.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lack of willingness to change your categories is dogmatic, and your categories become chains that restrict your growth. On the other hand, your categories may change so wildly that they become meaningless and without something to anchor you, you fall into an endless abyss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p style="text-align:left">
Perhaps, the most important category you&amp;#8217;ll construct is one of yourself.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every category you impose one the world is one that you also impose on yourself and you decide if you do or don’t fit into that category.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-05-21-611/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:24:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-05-21-611/</guid><description>&lt;p>These days I started listening the podcast, A.J. Hoge is very good, his talking is understandable and knowledgable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Notes: The Now Habit (1)</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-03-26-notes-the-now-habit-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 07:44:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-03-26-notes-the-now-habit-1/</guid><description>&lt;p style="text-align: right;">
Goal: supportive of yourself
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The questions about yourself:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Obligation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Time (vague terms such as “sometime next week” )&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Goals and value. (distracted by another plan)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Mood, fear.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Conclusion: Our real distress comes from constant anxiety of delaying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is important to notice the healing system. But Why we procrastinate? Because we fear a threat to our independence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fear of judgment is the key fear that stems from over-identifying who you are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two Years Anniversary of Using Anki</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-03-25-two-years-anniversary-of-using-anki/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 13:10:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-03-25-two-years-anniversary-of-using-anki/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="../uploads/2019/03/Anki.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been using Anki for two years.&lt;br>
It is one of the best learning and memorizing software I have ever met. It is open-source, freedom and personal.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image">
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="../uploads/2019/03/DeepinScreenshot_select-area_20190325204406.png"> &lt;/figure>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="../uploads/2019/03/DeepinScreenshot_select-area_20190325204509.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have added 18,000 cards in the English desk, making my English from slag to intermediate level where I can read English articles.&lt;br>
I also created other types of desks, related to my major and my interests.&lt;br>
The next steps are to improve my knowledge base of my major: create cards I should memorize, check my cards’ grammar and add some necessary pictures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/about-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 03:14:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/about-me/</guid><description>&lt;p>Writing is supposed to be an essential part of life. Organizing one’s words and works in the form of a blog is less fickle than social media-style sharing, and there are no more meaningless likes and comments; compared to keeping it private for oneself, and sharing it with those who need it. I created this blog to record myself and share my thoughts, articles and works. ：)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This site has joined the &lt;a href="https://foreverblog.cn/">Ten-year Contract activities&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>