<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Ten Arguments for Deleting Your Social Media Accounts Right Now on Liu Qiran</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/tags/ten-arguments-for-deleting-your-social-media-accounts-right-now/</link><description>Recent content in Ten Arguments for Deleting Your Social Media Accounts Right Now on Liu Qiran</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 14:56:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://liuqiran.github.io/en/tags/ten-arguments-for-deleting-your-social-media-accounts-right-now/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ARGUMENT THREE: SOCIAL MEDIA IS MAKING YOU INTO AN ASSHOLE</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-10-31-argument-three-social-media-is-making-you-into-an-asshole-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 14:56:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-10-31-argument-three-social-media-is-making-you-into-an-asshole-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SOOTY SNOW&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
You are more vulnerable when you get addicted.&lt;br>
You will become a poor or little snowflake.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>MEETING MY INNER TROLL&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The author said BUMMER causes two extremes, be an asshole or be very careful.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>THE MYSTERIOUS NATURE OF ASSHOLE AMPLIFICATION TECHNOLOGY&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
we need to be solitary wolves rather than wolves in packs. When we are in the pack, we cannot think individuality, but in a group cult.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>THE MOST MASTERFUL MASTER SWITCH&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Rather than Facebook or Twitter, LinkedIn built a high environment because there is no reason to catch your attention.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>GO TO WHERE YOU ARE KINDEST&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Don’t let your character degrade. When you latch on a platform, you always get irritable.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>When people are fake, everything becomes fake&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
You can’t even know who is real people.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>BUMMER kills&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
BUMMER made people believe fake things. Some people don’t believe vaccines, then once-defeated diseases revived.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ARGUMENT TWO: QUITTING SOCIAL MEDIA IS THE MOST FINELY TARGETED WAY TO RESIST THE INSANITY OF OUR TIMES</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-07-argument-two-quitting-social-media-is-the-most-finely-targeted-way-to-resist-the-insanity-of-our-times/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 14:05:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-07-argument-two-quitting-social-media-is-the-most-finely-targeted-way-to-resist-the-insanity-of-our-times/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>THE BUMMER MACHINE&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The better analogy for social media is paint contains lead in a house.&lt;br>
BUMMER: “Behaviors of Users Modified, and Made into an Empire for Rent”&lt;br>
&lt;strong>THE PARTS THAT MAKE UP THE BUMMER MACHINE&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Ais for Attention Acquisition leading to Asshole supremacy: this makes people online all nasty.&lt;br>
B Information and data always being recorded.&lt;br>
The BUMMER machine also makes the tech giant stronger, and it also creates a fake world.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>THE PROBLEM IS LIMITED, SO WE CAN CONTAIN IT&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
BUMMER is the problem to avoid, we need to delete BUMMER accounts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ARGUMENT ONE: YOU ARE LOSING YOUR FREE WILL</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-04-argument-one-you-are-losing-your-free-will/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 05:50:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-04-argument-one-you-are-losing-your-free-will/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="welcome-to-the-cage-that-goes-everywhere-with-you">WELCOME TO THE CAGE THAT GOES EVERYWHERE WITH YOU&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We are remotely controlled like animals in cages. We even don’t know that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-mad-scientist-turns-out-to-care-about-the-dog-in-the-cage">THE MAD SCIENTIST TURNS OUT TO CARE ABOUT THE DOG IN THE CAGE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The silicon valley gradually realizes the problem, but we cannot wait for them to solve this problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="carrot-and-shtick">Carrot and shtick&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Not only the pleasing kind, but punishment can also play an important role in addiction.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>