<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Liu Qiran</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Liu Qiran</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 22:04:54 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why do people find it harder to be emotionally stirred as they grow older?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025-05-10-why-do-people-find-it-harder-to-be-emotionally-stirred-as-they-grow-older/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025-05-10-why-do-people-find-it-harder-to-be-emotionally-stirred-as-they-grow-older/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because you came late, too late, even past mealtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost of entering someone&amp;rsquo;s heart doubles with age. At fifteen, a simple glance back can become a lifelong precious memory. At forty, even someone who manages both work and housework is just another part of life&amp;rsquo;s struggles. As children, playing in the dirt could create lifelong friendships, but as adults, today&amp;rsquo;s sworn brothers might stab you in the back tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 12 Repetition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-07-25-ep-12-repetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 12:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-07-25-ep-12-repetition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Repetition is an essential part in our life.&lt;br&gt;
Life is started from one cell. But just by copying itself, one cell can grow into a complicate system with different features. It’s a form of repetition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we need to memorize something, we aIso need a lot of repetitions. Maybe it’s very boring, but I can’t deny it’s a very effective way.&lt;br&gt;
When we need to gain a skill, we also need a lot of repetitions. We usually started from a very basic practice. Only after enough times of practice, we can learn more advanced skill.&lt;br&gt;
At first, even a basic skill is challenging to us, After enough repetition, it will become more and more easier. Then based on this skill there can growing more advanced skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cash</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-07-18-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 15:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-07-18-cash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a wallet and started using cash again recently.
It’s a very interesting try. I’ve been getting used to pay by smartphone for many years. It’s feeling weird after suddenly giving up E-pay. But now I found that I can still be relaxed when I going out without smartphone.
When I was paying, the feeling of “touching money” is very authentic. Compare with just tapping on the phone, I prefer the feeling of real money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 8 Real wealth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-05-30-ep-8-real-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 15:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-05-30-ep-8-real-wealth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wealth is usually considered to be money. But in my opinion, true wealth does not only contain money. It can contain many things, such as health, wisdom, and experience.&lt;br&gt;
An essential part of wealth is health. We inherited our health from our ancestors when we were born. It’s innate and priceless. But we can partially change it. We can destroy health, but we can also increase it.&lt;br&gt;
Another part of wealth is wisdom. Although our health can be inherited, we can’t inherit wisdom. Through learning, reading, and education, we can gradually get wisdom. Everyone has their own wisdom. It’s also priceless in different people’s lives.&lt;br&gt;
Finally, experience is also a part of wealth. Good experience is wealth, and bad experience is a kind of debt. But whether it is good or bad, whether it is a wealth or a liability, all depends on how you look at yourself. Everybody has unique experiences. If we can get more experience, we might be able to handle challenges more easily in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 7 Practice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-05-16-ep-7-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 17:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-05-16-ep-7-practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Practice is one of the most important things in our life.&lt;br&gt;
In order to gain our skill or improve our ability, we all need to have enough practice.&lt;br&gt;
Practice is repeated action. Enough times of repetition is necessary in our life. If we do a lot of practice, we will definitely get some improvements unconsciously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In most cases, the beginning of the practice is very difficult. We think it’s hard, it’s a big challenge. We may have tried many times, but there are still no results at all. We want to give up. But if we continue and persevere, as the times of practice increase, our improvement will be faster and faster. This is a phenomenon that shows up in many areas. The problem is that we give up so easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why don’t lie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-03-14-why-dont-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 23:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-03-14-why-dont-lie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we were kids, elders always tell us not to lie. But most of us lie because we are afraid of the consequences after telling the truths. As a child, lying is a good protection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s always a bad habit to lie to yourself or to other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lying can distort our understanding of reality. When we lie to ourselves, at first we think we can avoid the difficulties or solve some problems. But we will gradually lose the ability to face the real world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update home page</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-02-08-update-home-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 11:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2023-02-08-update-home-page/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Added progress bars and more social icons for home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added the feature which can share posts on Mastodon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
