<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Liu Qiran</title>
    <link>//localhost:38815/en/categories/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Liu Qiran</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 16:03:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:38815/en/categories/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Harm from technology</title>
      <link>//localhost:38815/en/2023-08-29-harm-from-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 16:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:38815/en/2023-08-29-harm-from-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the real harmful radiation is from the devices in our daily life. When we are using our smartphone or other electronic tools, it’s possible to be exposed to radiation. Some people think the radition from phone is not enough to cause negative effect to our body. I take a sceptical attitude.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthy food</title>
      <link>//localhost:38815/en/2023-08-15-healthy-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 15:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:38815/en/2023-08-15-healthy-food/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Healthy food: Salmon, saurekrout, pecan, olive oil, (cod) liver, arugula, hamburger meat. These foods have the highest nutrients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complicate physical activities</title>
      <link>//localhost:38815/en/2023-05-23-complicate-physical-activities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 15:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:38815/en/2023-05-23-complicate-physical-activities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, simple physical activities are not enough to improve mental health.&lt;br&gt;
As human beings, we get used to coordinate with our mind and body. Repeated and easy activities are boring. If the activities are more complicated, it’s better for our mentality. We can also combine different activities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expo</title>
      <link>//localhost:38815/en/2019-07-05-expo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 13:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:38815/en/2019-07-05-expo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I went to Yanqing visiting the 2019 Expo. But the weather was bad, it often rains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think my physical condition is still not very good, I can try to build a habit of washing cold water. Washing cold water can build up cardiopulmonary function and improve my immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;退休教师97岁了还能干农活 坚持洗冷水澡&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;每天要用冷水洗澡，每个月都要出去旅游，虽然年近百岁，但依然身轻体健，干农活也不在话下……在宁波余姚牟山镇魏家村的吴昂头，吴国靖老人远近闻名，大家在为他的健康长寿啧啧称赞的同时，也对他的长寿秘诀感到好奇。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;吴国靖今年97岁，当记者见到他时，很难相信他竟然是一个快100岁的老人。当天，他穿着一身整洁的衣裳，带着一顶鸭舌帽，脸色红润有光泽，手上和脸上的皱纹也不是很多，只是听力稍差。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;吴国靖退休前是一名小学教师，他喜欢看报纸和杂志，还自创了一套早操，每天早上都会做一做。至于为什么会想到用冷水洗澡，吴国靖告诉记者，78岁那一年，他在电视上看到一个80多岁的老人跳进冰河里救人的新闻，得知老人之所以有那么好的身体，是因为平时经常冬泳，这给了他很大的启发。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“于是，从那个时候起，我每天用自家的井水洗澡，无论刮风下雨还是严寒酷暑，一直坚持到现在。”吴国靖说，“冷水洗澡的好处就是可以增强抵抗力，还会增强血管弹性、预防动脉硬化，促进新陈代谢，使皮肤变得柔软、有弹性。而且我在洗澡的时候还会用毛巾使劲搓，起到按摩的效果，这样越洗越热，一点也不冷。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;吴国靖的儿媳妇严雅娟告诉记者，老人非常爱干净，每次从地里回来就会洗澡，多的时候一天要洗三次，而且每个月他都会和孩子们一起出去旅游，一点都没觉得累。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“上次我们去绍兴的兜率天宫玩，那么高的山，年轻人都不想爬上去，而我爸坚持要爬，我们怎么也跟不上他的脚步。跟团出去玩，如果我们不说我爸的年纪，都没人会相信他已经97岁了。”严雅娟笑着说。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;吴国靖82岁的时候动过一次小手术，当时为他检查身体的医生说，他的体质还只有60岁。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;说起自己健康长寿的秘诀，吴国靖认为，除了用冷水洗澡，还要注意四点：合理膳食、规律生活、适当锻炼、心态平衡。每天吃完早餐，吴国靖就背上锄头去地里干农活了，松松土、拔拔草、浇浇水，一干就是一上午。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“我爸做起农活来常常会忘记时间，吃午饭都要我们去叫。”严雅娟说，“吃完午饭睡会儿午觉，就又去田里干活了。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;什么时候起床、什么时候吃饭、什么时候睡觉，吴国靖都有自己的时间表，空余的时候他就看看电视和杂志。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“我不抽烟也不喝酒，平时以素食为主，家里的小孩对我都非常孝敬，孙子辈都已经很大了，活到这把年纪也没什么好操心的，放宽心，自己照顾好自己就好咯！”吴国靖笑着说。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;转载自:甬派客户端&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
