<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on Liu Qiran</title>
    <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/tags/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on Liu Qiran</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:52:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://liuqiran.github.io/en/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>EP 14 Information quality</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-22-ep-14-information-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-08-22-ep-14-information-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my own opinion, there are three kinds of information in our life.&lt;br&gt;
The first one is text, the second is audio, the last one is video.&lt;br&gt;
Let’s talk about the first one. The content of texts is based on words. It’s the most abstract form of information. If we are literate, we can understand words, then we can understand road signs, posters, magazines, and books. It’s simplest to save texts for us. It’s also a form that can save the best information quality. But it’s maybe the hardest information to understand. Books contain the deepest information quality.&lt;br&gt;
Audio is another kind of information, it’s based on sounds. It’s more natural to us because we can use our ear to understand. But we can’t control the speed of understanding. We probably also receive some useless information.&lt;br&gt;
The third one is video. It combines sound and image. We can understand it very well, but it’s more shallow. Normally, information quality of video is not that good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 12 Repetition</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-25-ep-12-repetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 12:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-25-ep-12-repetition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Repetition is an essential part in our life.&lt;br&gt;
Life is started from one cell. But just by copying itself, one cell can grow into a complicate system with different features. It’s a form of repetition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we need to memorize something, we aIso need a lot of repetitions. Maybe it’s very boring, but I can’t deny it’s a very effective way.&lt;br&gt;
When we need to gain a skill, we also need a lot of repetitions. We usually started from a very basic practice. Only after enough times of practice, we can learn more advanced skill.&lt;br&gt;
At first, even a basic skill is challenging to us, After enough repetition, it will become more and more easier. Then based on this skill there can growing more advanced skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 11 Pure writing</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-11-ep-11-pure-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 13:39:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-07-11-ep-11-pure-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-anchor-fm-inc wp-block-embed-anchor-fm-inc&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-embed__wrapper&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing is a essential part in the life of thinking and learning. It’s also indispensible for me.&lt;br&gt;
But the way of writing has changed a lot. Writing on paper is the most traditional way.&lt;br&gt;
I can still vaguely remember the days when I was writing journal on paper under the dim light of lamp. I enjoyed the feeling of writing on paper.&lt;br&gt;
But it’s very inconvenient to write on paper. We can’t take all of our notebooks easily. It’s also difficult to look up former words.&lt;br&gt;
I started writing on note-taking apps in 2016. It’s really convenient and solved the former problems.&lt;br&gt;
There are a lot of features on noke-taking apps. We can change the style and font of notes. We can insert images, audios, even attachments of any format…&lt;br&gt;
But in recent years I realized I spent so much time on the features of the software. It created a lot of difficulties to saving and sharing. Another problem is that, note-taking app is installed on electronic devices. Phones and computers contains more features and notifcations. Now I think this way of writing also has its negative effect. It will create a lot of distractions.&lt;br&gt;
Recently I started writing in plain text. I can write in any note-taking softwares. Using special device for writing is also a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 10 Temporary guest</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-27-ep-10-temporary-guest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 15:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-27-ep-10-temporary-guest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I was organizing my contact information. I found a lot of people I haven’t contacted in a long time. As time goes by, they disappear from my life and never reappear. It’s as if they died even though I have their information. Each of them is like a temporary guest. I don’t know if there will be a chance for us to meet in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m gradually able to start a new relationship. But at the moment I still don’t have the ability to reconnect with old people, but I’m trying my best. I feel that many people don’t have this ability because of embarrassment. We just let these relationships die one by one. I don’t want to be isolated, so to avoid that situation, I also have to overcome my fear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 9 Technical breakdown</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-13-ep-9-technical-breakdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 14:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-06-13-ep-9-technical-breakdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I went through a serious problem of my server, on which my website runs.&lt;br&gt;
It started with the problem of the version of PHP. The edition of the current PHP is very old and it couldn’t support the running of some plugins. Then I tried to install a new version of PHP, but it didn’t work. When I tried to uninstall the old version, the server crashed and could not be restarted due to an error called “kernel panic”.&lt;br&gt;
I’ve done my best to fix it myself until midnight. It’s useless. I could only ask other people for help. The technical staff couldn’t solve it either, but they helped me to backup the data. It’s a very tedious experience and I could restore my server after several days. Finally, I used the backup data and restored my website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 8 Real wealth</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-30-ep-8-real-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 15:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-30-ep-8-real-wealth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wealth is usually considered to be money. But in my opinion, true wealth does not only contain money. It can contain many things, such as health, wisdom, and experience.&lt;br&gt;
An essential part of wealth is health. We inherited our health from our ancestors when we were born. It’s innate and priceless. But we can partially change it. We can destroy health, but we can also increase it.&lt;br&gt;
Another part of wealth is wisdom. Although our health can be inherited, we can’t inherit wisdom. Through learning, reading, and education, we can gradually get wisdom. Everyone has their own wisdom. It’s also priceless in different people’s lives.&lt;br&gt;
Finally, experience is also a part of wealth. Good experience is wealth, and bad experience is a kind of debt. But whether it is good or bad, whether it is a wealth or a liability, all depends on how you look at yourself. Everybody has unique experiences. If we can get more experience, we might be able to handle challenges more easily in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 7 Practice</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-16-ep-7-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 17:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-16-ep-7-practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Practice is one of the most important things in our life.&lt;br&gt;
In order to gain our skill or improve our ability, we all need to have enough practice.&lt;br&gt;
Practice is repeated action. Enough times of repetition is necessary in our life. If we do a lot of practice, we will definitely get some improvements unconsciously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In most cases, the beginning of the practice is very difficult. We think it’s hard, it’s a big challenge. We may have tried many times, but there are still no results at all. We want to give up. But if we continue and persevere, as the times of practice increase, our improvement will be faster and faster. This is a phenomenon that shows up in many areas. The problem is that we give up so easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 6 Plain text</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-02-ep-6-plain-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 15:03:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-05-02-ep-6-plain-text/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have used a lot of software to store my notes and data. But gradually I found that although these softwares are very convenient and they offer a lot of good services. They also caused me a lot of trouble in the long run.&lt;br&gt;
One important reason is that you cannot export your data freely. I tried a lot of softwares after I decided to write online. Many of them don’t provide good export service. Your files can only be exported to some special formats. What’s more, these files can only be viewed in some special forms. We can probably convert them to other formats we want, but it’s not that easy.&lt;br&gt;
Another reason is that I realized that some tools and services could give you a lot of convenience and unique features, but when you get used to it. You are also limited by these tools. Your choice would be less, and it’s also very inconvenient if you want to change your tool. Especially for a person who is always curious about new tools. Technology is a double-edged sword. I always want to find a suitable tool for writing, learning, productivity, etc. But the result is not so good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 5 Thirteen years of journaling</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-18-ep-5-thirteen-years-of-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 09:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-18-ep-5-thirteen-years-of-journaling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been journaling for thirteen years.&lt;br&gt;
I started journaling in April 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s one of the most important habits in my life.&lt;br&gt;
Before 2016, I wrote journals on paper. After 2016, I started to write on app. It’s very convenient to write digitally. After December 2017, I started writing in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I became aware that journals are the history of my own life.&lt;br&gt;
Now I have the intention to collect all my journals and publish them in a book. I think it would be very interesting to browse through my whole life.&lt;br&gt;
Looking back to my childhood, I realized that I already have the talent to collect the materials in different periods and save them in order. I enjoyed that kind of feeling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 4 AI tool for learning</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-04-ep-4-ai-tool-for-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 20:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-04-04-ep-4-ai-tool-for-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m Qiran. Today, I would like to share with you my understanding of Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gradually realized that AI has already entered my life. Some people may think that AI is very destructive to the lives of ordinary people. But in my opinion, the most distinct characteristic that humans possess and surpass other creatures is the ability to use tools. AI is a very useful tool now, and it would be highly beneficial if we can learn to use it effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 3 Feel the fear</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-21-ep-3-feel-the-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 11:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-21-ep-3-feel-the-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Qiran. Today I would like to share with you my understanding of fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear is one of the basic human emotions. We all have fears. As for me, fear is one of my biggest difficulties in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different kinds of fear.&lt;br&gt;
The first fear of myself is the fear of being disappointed by others. In terms of human relationships, I’m really an infant now. I am afraid of falling.&lt;br&gt;
I always avoid dealing with others, just like an infant avoids learning to walk. But if I never fall down, I cannot learn to walk forever.&lt;br&gt;
I knew I had to accept disappointments. Maybe I’m able to collect them in order to develop my abilities. I don’t have to take them personally. Disappointments are actually assets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP 2 The tree of habits</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-07-ep-2-the-tree-of-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 03:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-03-07-ep-2-the-tree-of-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Qiran. Today I would like to share with you some of my understanding about habits.&lt;br&gt;
In my life, the concept of cultivating habits is gradually becoming one of the most important parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, habit is a compound interest. The fruits or effects of habits will grow faster and faster in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, one of the examples of daily habit is writing journals. Maybe it’s my longest habit, which started from my middle school time. Now it has become my important habit that records my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP-01 Why I start my podcast</title>
      <link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-21-ep-01-why-i-start-my-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 15:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2023-02-21-ep-01-why-i-start-my-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone. I’m Qiran. This is the first episode of my podcast. Today’s topic is that, I want to share reasons about why I start my podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first reason is, it’s a place of sharing my thoughts and my understanding covering a lot of topics. It’s an opportunity to exchange ideas with others, maybe I can meet new friends and learn a lot from others in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I think I can cover a lot of topics that I’m interested in. Forcing myself to write something is a good habit to learn, and it’ll also help me improve my thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
