<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Masochism and the Self on </title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/en/categories/masochism-and-the-self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Masochism and the Self on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.1</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 22:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/en/categories/masochism-and-the-self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Masochism, Culture, and History</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/2019-09-22-masochism-culture-and-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/2019-09-22-masochism-culture-and-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self in history&lt;/strong&gt;: Before the Renaissance, self is not appeared by the control of religion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/2019-08-30-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 02:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/2019-08-30-self/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High levels are abstract. People alway want to go higher level thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shifting to low levels has two benefits, the first is people can avoid the control of high levels, the second is, people escape from strong emotions like anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People usually change between high levels and low levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-awareness can occurs at different levels, at low levels, like pain and movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-worth is very important if they cannot justify their actions and feel progress for their goals, self-worth will be very low.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Masochism and sadism</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/2019-07-17-masochism-and-sadism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 06:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/2019-07-17-masochism-and-sadism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Freud’s theory, masochism is from sadism, another theory said that sadism and masochism are two faces of one coin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the recent study shows that maybe masochism is more fundamental. The number of Masochists are much more than sadists’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The submissive partners are really in control during SM, because it is the submissive’s desire shapes the sex play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Masochistic desires are much stronger than sadistic. But many submissive people cannot find a partner to dominate them because of the shortage. So What happens often is two masochists meet each other, one of them should take turns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
