<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>English on</title><link>https://liuqiran.com/en/categories/english/</link><description>Recent content in English on</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.140.1</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 13:39:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://liuqiran.com/en/categories/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>EP 11 Pure writing</title><link>https://liuqiran.com/en/2023-07-11-ep-11-pure-writing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 13:39:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.com/en/2023-07-11-ep-11-pure-writing/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-anchor-fm-inc wp-block-embed-anchor-fm-inc">
&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Writing is a essential part in the life of thinking and learning. It’s also indispensible for me.&lt;br>
But the way of writing has changed a lot. Writing on paper is the most traditional way.&lt;br>
I can still vaguely remember the days when I was writing journal on paper under the dim light of lamp. I enjoyed the feeling of writing on paper.&lt;br>
But it’s very inconvenient to write on paper. We can’t take all of our notebooks easily. It’s also difficult to look up former words.&lt;br>
I started writing on note-taking apps in 2016. It’s really convenient and solved the former problems.&lt;br>
There are a lot of features on noke-taking apps. We can change the style and font of notes. We can insert images, audios, even attachments of any format…&lt;br>
But in recent years I realized I spent so much time on the features of the software. It created a lot of difficulties to saving and sharing. Another problem is that, note-taking app is installed on electronic devices. Phones and computers contains more features and notifcations. Now I think this way of writing also has its negative effect. It will create a lot of distractions.&lt;br>
Recently I started writing in plain text. I can write in any note-taking softwares. Using special device for writing is also a good idea.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Written Assignment #2</title><link>https://liuqiran.com/en/2019-12-09-written-assignment-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:01:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.com/en/2019-12-09-written-assignment-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Translation&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The Master said to Yan Yuan, “If I’m employed, I’ll show my talent; If not, I’ll hide my light under a bushel, only you and I have the ability to do it!”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zi Lu said, “If you lead troops, whom do you want to work with you?” &lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Master Said, “If someone attacks a tiger unarmed or crosses a river without a boat, and he died without any regret, I would not work with him. What I need definitely is someone who is careful and fond of making plans for success.”&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Brief Overview of 19th Century English</title><link>https://liuqiran.com/en/2019-11-04-a-brief-overview-of-19th-century-english/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 12:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.com/en/2019-11-04-a-brief-overview-of-19th-century-english/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google Books Ngram Viewer&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Ngram&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Commonly called an Ngram&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statistical analysis of text or speech&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finds n(a number) of a certain item in  text (examples of n: phonemes, prefixes,  phrases, or letters)&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Google Books Ngram Viewer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
analyzed text (‘corpus’): books scanned  by Google&lt;br>
default time period: 1800 to 2000 output: graph representing use of  searched item in books through time (used in this presentation to show general  trends of increase or decrease of usage  from the 19th c.)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="historical-background-lohr">Historical Background (Lohr)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p class="has-text-color has-dark-gray-color">
Old English (Anglo-Saxon): &lt;strong>5th ­-11th&lt;/strong> centuries&lt;br />Since c. 450 CE, West Germanic peoples&amp;nbsp; settle southern Britain
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://liuqiran.com/en/2019-05-21-611/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:24:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.com/en/2019-05-21-611/</guid><description>&lt;p>These days I started listening the podcast, A.J. Hoge is very good, his talking is understandable and knowledgable.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>