<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Antifragile: Things That Gain From Disorder on Liu Qiran</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/tags/antifragile-things-that-gain-from-disorder/</link><description>Recent content in Antifragile: Things That Gain From Disorder on Liu Qiran</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 11:56:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://liuqiran.github.io/en/tags/antifragile-things-that-gain-from-disorder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHAPTER 6 Tell Them I Love (Some) Randomness</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-08-chapter-6-tell-them-i-love-some-randomness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 11:56:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-03-08-chapter-6-tell-them-i-love-some-randomness/</guid><description>&lt;p>When the variation comes, people will rush into the door.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>HUNGRY DONKEYS&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Equal distance between food and water makes donkey die of hunger or thirst.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Political Annealing&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The problem of the United States is the two-party system, you cannot randomize a party that doesn’t exist.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>The Second Step: Do (Small) Wars Save Lives?&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Maybe the small wars or some battles strengthen the country.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>What to Tell the Foreign Policy Makers&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Saudi Arabia and the US formed an alliance for stability, but it’s very dangerous in the long run. Royalties controlled the whole country, but this alliance strengthens the fundamentalism underground. Maybe the country will get into a more disastrous situation in the future.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>WHAT DO WE CALL HERE MODERNITY?&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
We are moving into a period of modernity of MBA, lobbyist, secularization, etc.&lt;br>
The taxman, fear of the boss, and separate the work and leisure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHAPTER 5 The Souk and the Office Building</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-14-chapter-5-the-souk-and-the-office-building/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 12:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-02-14-chapter-5-the-souk-and-the-office-building/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>TWO TYPES OF PROFESSIONS&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
There are two types of professions, employee and taxi driver, though the first one has a high salary and stable, it’s fragile. This profession is in a system of artificial and human-made. But the second one is antifragile, same kind profession corporates artisan, prostitute, etc. Nature like small mistakes and variability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Lenin in Zurich&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Because Swiss have no government, it formed a bottom-up system that causes stability. There is no big idea that can generate in this country. It’s a magnet for ugly rich and tax refugees.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Kills Me Makes Others Stronger</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-10-what-kills-me-makes-others-stronger/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 05:33:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2020-01-10-what-kills-me-makes-others-stronger/</guid><description>&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="antifragility-by-layers">Antifragility by layers&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Some parts on the inside of a system may be required to be fragile in order to make the system antifragile as a result.&lt;/em> All restaurants are combating with each other in order to form the antifragility of the whole group. If a single restaurant is too robust when the crisis happens, all reasons are boil down to the fragile of this restaurant.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="evolution-and-unpredictability">Evolution and Unpredictability&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Nature (and nature-like systems) likes diversity between organisms rather than diversity within an immortal organism…&lt;/em>&lt;br>
Evolutions benefits from the randomness but the unit died from the harms.&lt;br>
So I need to build some new systems different than the habit system, such as an energy managing system or log system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Cat and the Washing Machine</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-29-the-cat-and-the-washing-machine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 12:59:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-29-the-cat-and-the-washing-machine/</guid><description>&lt;p>organic and mechanical are different, organisms are antifragile, also for human-beings. But in modern society, humans all live longer but weak, because the environment is so fragile. Unlike natural environment, their working environment, medicine and living quarters all making them weaker and weaker. Unlike mechanicals, organisms will become stronger because of self-repair in some point.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-complex">The Complex&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The man-made mechanicals are complicated but not complex, If you break them down, they don’t cause a ripple effect. But human society or ecology is complex, if you exterminate a specific animal, you will disrupt a food chain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overcompensation and Overreaction Everywhere</title><link>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-27-overcompensation-and-overreaction-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 06:24:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liuqiran.github.io/en/2019-11-27-overcompensation-and-overreaction-everywhere/</guid><description>&lt;p>If as want to innovate and get creativities, we must get in trouble first, we cannot get invention from comfort.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-to-win-a-horse-race">HOW TO WIN A HORSE RACE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If we want to finish a task, we must finish it in our busiest time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="antifragile-responses-as-redundancy">Antifragile Responses as Redundancy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>the human’s kidney is a form of redundancy, it isn’t useless, because you can save for bad times. So it’s the same reason why we need to build strong will and get in trouble even though there is no hazard.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>