<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Literary Mind and the Carving of Dragons on </title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/en/categories/the-literary-mind-and-the-carving-of-dragons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Literary Mind and the Carving of Dragons on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.2</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 01:52:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/en/categories/the-literary-mind-and-the-carving-of-dragons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction 1</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/2020-05-13-introduction-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 01:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/2020-05-13-introduction-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wang Ch’ung displays a liberalism unique. He thik the present is better than the past, same as Ge Hong.&lt;br&gt;
Cao Cao, was a competent poet. Cao Pi, 典論論文&lt;br&gt;
蕭統，he accounted for excluding the Classics and historical works from his anthology, because they were not pure literature.&lt;br&gt;
徐陵，玉臺新詠&lt;br&gt;
Cao Pi consider that Qi, is born with us, it cannot be changed by instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;陸機 文賦&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;All external vision and sound are suspended,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Perpetual thought itself gropes in time and space;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Then, the spirit at full gallop reaches the eight limits of the cosmos,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;And the mind, self-buoyant, will ever soar to new unsurmountable heights.&lt;/em&gt; Through arduous work, we can reach the artistic impulse.&lt;br&gt;
Great Void, Profound Silence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Questions about Wenxin Diaolong</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/2020-04-08-questions-about-wenxin-diaolong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/2020-04-08-questions-about-wenxin-diaolong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;一、此文中如何理解“气”的美学意义？“气”这个概念为何对于艺术创作来说格外重要？&lt;br&gt;
天地人的世界，不僅遵循著一致性原則，同樣也遵循類比性原則。它是一種主客互攝式的一體式的關係。“傍及萬品，动植皆文……”氣學的解释話語可涵蓋文學活动的各個方面。氣的這種自由出入、實象與虛境化合、包容萬有的質性十分契合藝術活动的本質特征。“神远”與“虛靜”开啓了客體與主體整體融和的一種境界，是中國式的意會體悟的言說方式。氣的一體兩面的特征貫通文學世界與形上世界。&lt;br&gt;
造藝者的知、情、志、意的心理活动的整體性消融與化合，是需要借助于氣之關聯與貫通，纔可達致內外世界的和諧統一。“氣無奇類，文乏異采”、“氣偉而采奇”說明氣乃是構建文字、語言、辞采的前提。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;二、此文中讲到的刘勰“江山之助”论的思想内涵有哪些可能？他最后同意哪一种来源？&lt;br&gt;
江山有抒發郁拂寥廓之氣，可直接詮释為貶謫。從根本上看，要在天、人之際達到平衡，不僅需要自然景物的陶冶，還要現實生活的感發，因此江山不等同於“山林皋壤”，而是指社会政治因素，這也是成就屈原《離騒》的更重要的內因。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XXVII. Style and Nature</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/2020-03-07-xxvii-style-and-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 10:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/2020-03-07-xxvii-style-and-nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The style and nature need to be fitted with each other, the outer and the inner realities always correspond.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
